<?xml version="1.0" encoding="US-ASCII"?>
<!DOCTYPE rfc SYSTEM "rfc2629.dtd">
<?rfc toc="yes"?>
<?rfc tocompact="yes"?>
<?rfc tocdepth="3"?>
<?rfc tocindent="yes"?>
<?rfc symrefs="yes"?>
<?rfc sortrefs="yes"?>
<?rfc comments="yes"?>
<?rfc inline="yes"?>
<?rfc compact="yes"?>
<?rfc subcompact="no"?>
<?rfc private="Draft"?>
<rfc category="exp" docName="atomactivity-00" ipr="none">
  <front>
    <title abbrev="ActivitySchema">Atom Activity Base Schema (Draft)</title>

    <author fullname="Martin Atkins" initials="M." surname="Atkins">
      <organization>Six Apart</organization>
    </author>

    <author fullname="David Recordon" initials="D." surname="Recordon">
      <organization>Six Apart, Facebook</organization>
    </author>

    <author fullname="Chris Messina" initials="C." surname="Messina">
      <organization>Citizen Agency, Google</organization>
    </author>

    <author fullname="Monica Keller" initials="M." surname="Keller">
      <organization>MySpace, Facebook</organization>
    </author>

    <author fullname="Ari Steinberg" initials="A." surname="Steinberg">
      <organization>Facebook</organization>
    </author>

    <author fullname="Rob Dolin" initials="R." surname="Dolin">
      <organization>Microsoft</organization>
    </author>

    <date />

    <abstract>
      <t>This document presents a base set of Object types and Verbs for use
      with Atom Activity Extensions.</t>
    </abstract>

    <note title="Requirements Language">
      <t>The key words "MUST", "MUST NOT", "REQUIRED", "SHALL", "SHALL NOT",
      "SHOULD", "SHOULD NOT", "RECOMMENDED", "MAY", and "OPTIONAL" in this
      document are to be interpreted as described in <xref
      target="RFC2119">RFC 2119</xref>.</t>
    </note>
  </front>

  <middle>
    <section title="Introduction">
      <t>This document presents a base set of Object types and Verbs for use
      with Atom Activity Extensions.</t>
    </section>

    <section title="Notational Conventions">
      <t>In this document, the following namespace prefixes are used for the
      given namespace URI from the referenced specification:</t>

      <texttable>
        <ttcol>Alias</ttcol>

        <ttcol>Namespace URI</ttcol>

        <ttcol>Specification</ttcol>

        <c><spanx style="verb">atom:</spanx></c>

        <c><spanx style="verb">http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom</spanx></c>

        <c><xref target="RFC4287">The Atom Syndication Format</xref></c>

        <c><spanx style="verb">thr:</spanx></c>

        <c><spanx style="verb">http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0</spanx></c>

        <c><xref target="RFC4685">Atom Threading Extensions</xref></c>

        <c><spanx style="verb">activity:</spanx></c>

        <c><spanx style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/</spanx></c>

        <c>Atom Activity Extensions</c>

        <c><spanx style="verb">media:</spanx></c>

        <c><spanx style="verb">http://purl.org/syndication/atommedia</spanx></c>

        <c>Atom Media Extensions</c>

        <c><spanx style="verb">cal:</spanx></c>

        <c><spanx style="verb">urn:ietf:params:xml:ns:xcal</spanx></c>

        <c>xCal</c>

        <c><spanx style="verb">pc:</spanx></c>

        <c><spanx style="verb">http://portablecontacts.net/schema/1.0</spanx></c>

        <c>PortableContacts</c>

        <c><spanx style="verb">geo:</spanx></c>

        <c><spanx style="verb">http://www.georss.org/georss</spanx></c>

        <c>GeoRSS</c>
      </texttable>

      <t>The choices of namespace prefix are arbitrary and not semantically
      significant.</t>

      <t>This specification uses a shorthand form of terms from the XML
      Infoset [W3C.REC-xml-infoset-20040204]. The phrase "Information Item" is
      omitted when naming Element and Attribute Information Items. Therefore,
      when this specification uses the term "element," it is referring to an
      Element Information Item in Infoset terms. Likewise, when this
      specification uses the term "attribute," it is referring to an Attribute
      Information Item.</t>

      <t>This specification allows the use of IRIs [RFC3987]. Every URI
      [RFC3986] is also an IRI, so a URI MAY be used wherever an IRI is named.
      When an IRI that is not also a URI is given for dereferencing, it MUST
      be mapped to a URI using the steps in Section 3.1 of [RFC3987]. When an
      IRI is serving as an identifier, it MUST NOT be so mapped.</t>

      <t>Some sections of this specification are illustrated with a non-
      normative RELAX NG Compact schema [RELAXNG]. In those sections, this
      specification uses the atomCommonAttributes, atomMediaType, and atomURI
      patterns, defined in [RFC4287].</t>

      <t>However, the text of this specification provides the sole definition
      of conformance.</t>

      <t>This specification uses "the Atom specification" to refer to <xref
      target="RFC4287"></xref>, and "the AtomActivity specification" to refer
      to [insert xref here].</t>
    </section>

    <section title="Base Schema">
      <t>The base schema provides generic terms that all activity consumers
      SHOULD support. The other, more specific sections that follow use
      specializations of this base vocabulary to provide additional terms that
      may only be useful in certain applications.</t>

      <section title="Base Verbs">
        <section anchor="post" title="Post">
          <t>The "Post" Verb is described in section 8 of the AtomActivity
          specification. It is only referenced here for completeness.</t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="share" title="Share">
          <t>The "share" Verb indicates that the Subject has called out the
          Object to readers. In most cases, the actor did not create the
          Object being shared, but is instead drawing attention to it.</t>

          <t>The verb URI for the "share" Verb is <spanx style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/share</spanx>.</t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="save" title="Save">
          <t>The "save" Verb indicates that the Subject has called out the
          Object as being of interest primarily to him- or herself. Though
          this action MAY be shared publicly, the implication is that the
          Object has been saved primarily for the actor's own benefit rather
          than to show it to others as would be indicated by the "share" Verb
          (<xref target="share"></xref>).</t>

          <t>The verb URI for the "save" Verb is <spanx style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/save</spanx>.</t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="favorite" title="Mark as Favorite">
          <t>The "mark as favorite" Verb indicates that the Subject marked the
          Object as an item of special interest. Objects so marked often
          appear in a collection of such Objects which MAY be published as a
          feed of entries annotated with this Verb.</t>

          <t>If a particular service uses favorites as a mechanism by which a
          user can recall items that were earlier marked, it MAY be
          appropriate to also mark activities of this type with the "save"
          Verb as described in <xref target="save"></xref>.</t>

          <t>The verb URI for the "mark as favorite" Verb is <spanx
          style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/favorite</spanx>.</t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="like" title="Mark as Liked">
          <t>The "mark as liked" verb indicates that the actor indicated that
          it likes the object.</t>

          <t>The verb URI for the "mark as liked" Verb is <spanx style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/like</spanx>.</t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="play" title="Play">
          <t>The "play" verb indicates that the subject spent some time
          enjoying the object. For example, if the object is a video this
          indicates that the subject watched all or part of the video.</t>

          <t>The verb URI for the "play" Verb is <spanx style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/play</spanx>.</t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="follow" title="Start Following">
          <t>The "start following" Verb indicates that the Subject began
          following the activity of the Object. In most cases, the Object of
          this Verb will be a user, but it can potentially be of any type that
          can sensibly generate activity.</t>

          <t>The verb URI for the "start following" Verb is <spanx
          style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/follow</spanx>.</t>

          <t>Processors MAY ignore (silently drop) successive identical "start
          following" activities regardless of whether they maintain state
          sufficient to determine (A), (B), or (C) above.</t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="make-friend" title="Make Friend">
          <t>The "make friend" Verb indicates the creation of a friendship
          that is reciprocated by the object.</t>

          <t>Since this verb implies an activity on the part of its object,
          processors MUST NOT accept activities with this Verb unless they are
          able to verify through some external means that there is in fact a
          reciprocated connection. For example, a processor MAY have received
          a guarantee from a particular publisher that the publisher will only
          use this Verb in cases where a reciprocal relationship exists.</t>

          <t>The verb URI for the "make friend" Verb is <spanx style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/make-friend</spanx>.</t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="join" title="Join">
          <t>The "join" Verb indicates that the actor has become a member of
          the Object. This specification only defines the meaning of this Verb
          when its Object is a group, though implementors SHOULD be prepared
          to handle other Object types as meaning MAY be provided by extension
          specifications.</t>

          <t>Processors MAY ignore (silently drop) successive identical "join"
          activities regardless of whether they maintain state sufficient to
          determine (A) or (B) above.</t>

          <t>The verb URI for the "join" Verb is <spanx style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/join</spanx>.</t>
        </section>

        <section title="Tag">
          <t>The "tag" verb indicates that the actor has identified the
          presence of a target inside another object. For example, the actor
          may have specified that a particular user appears in a photo.</t>

          <t>The verb URI for the "tag" verb is <spanx style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/tag</spanx>.</t>

          <t>The target of the "tag" verb gives the object in which the tag
          has been added. For example, if a user appears in a photo, the
          activity:object is the user and the activity:target is the
          photo.</t>
        </section>
      </section>

      <section title="Base Object Types">
        <section anchor="article" title="Article">
          <t>The "article" Object type indicates that the Object is an
          article, such as a news article, a knowledge base entry, or other
          similar construct.</t>

          <t>Articles generally consist of paragraphs of text, in some cases
          incorporating embedded media such as photos and inline hyperlinks to
          other resources.</t>

          <t>The Object type URL for the "Article" Object type is <spanx
          style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/article</spanx>.</t>

          <t>An article has the following properties:</t>

          <t><list style="hanging">
              <t hangText="title">The title of the entry. Included as the
              content of the atom:title element. This element MUST be included
              with empty content if the entry does not have a title.</t>

              <t hangText="summary">A short excerpt of the body content that
              gives an introduction to or a summary of the full content. This
              element SHOULD be omitted if the entry does not have a
              summary.</t>

              <t hangText="content">The main body content of the entry.
              Included as the content of the atom:content element.</t>

              <t hangText="permalink">The canonical URL for the entry.
              Represented as the value of the <spanx style="verb">href</spanx>
              attribute on an <spanx style="verb">atom:link</spanx> element
              with a <spanx style="verb">rel</spanx> value of <spanx
              style="verb">alternate</spanx> and a <spanx style="verb">type</spanx>
              value of <spanx style="verb">text/html</spanx>.</t>
            </list></t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="blog-entry" title="Blog Entry">
          <t>The "blog entry" object type indicates that the Object is an
          entry in a blog or some other similar construct.</t>

          <t>The "blog entry" object type is a specialization of the "article"
          object type, so publishers SHOULD also include the object type URL
          for the "article" object type when publishing object entries of this
          type.</t>

          <t>The Object type URL for the "weblog entry" Object type is <spanx
          style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/blog-entry</spanx>.</t>

          <t>A weblog entry has all of the properties of an article as defined
          in <xref target="article"></xref>, and has no additional
          properties.</t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="note" title="Note">
          <t>The "note" Object type represents short-form text messages. This
          Object type is intended for use in "micro-blogging" and in systems
          where users are invited to publish short, often plain-text messages
          whose useful lifespan is generally shorter than that of an article
          or weblog entry.</t>

          <t>A note is similar in structure to an article, but it does not
          have a title and its body tends to be shorter. Applications will
          often display the entire content of a note in an activity stream UI,
          whereas they MAY display only the title or the title and summary for
          a weblog entry.</t>

          <t>The object type URL for the "note" Object type is <spanx
          style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</spanx>.</t>

          <t>A note has the following properties:</t>

          <t><list style="hanging">
              <t hangText="content">The content of the note. Included as the
              content of the atom:content element. Publishers SHOULD include
              any markup necessary to achieve a similar presentation to that
              on the publisher's own HTML pages, including any links that the
              service automatically adds. Processors MAY remove the markup and
              consider the note to be plain text.</t>

              <t hangText="permalink">The canonical URL for the note.
              Represented as the value of the <spanx style="verb">href</spanx>
              attribute on an <spanx style="verb">atom:link</spanx> element
              with a <spanx style="verb">rel</spanx> value of <spanx
              style="verb">alternate</spanx> and a <spanx style="verb">type</spanx>
              value of <spanx style="verb">text/html</spanx>.</t>
            </list></t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="status" title="Status">
          <t>The "status" Object type represents a human-readable update of
          the author's situation, mood, location or other status.</t>

          <t>A status is similar in structure to a note, but carries the
          additional meaning that the content is primarily describing
          something its author is doing, feeling or experiencing.</t>

          <t>A consumers MAY consider the content of the most recent status
          object it encountered to be the user's current status, unless the
          most recent status update is old. When a status becomes too old is
          not defined by this specification.</t>

          <t>The object type URL for the "status" object type is <spanx
          style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/status</spanx>.</t>

          <t>A note has the following properties:</t>

          <t><list style="hanging">
              <t hangText="content">The content of the status update. Included
              as the content of the atom:content element. Publishers SHOULD
              include any markup necessary to achieve a similar presentation
              to that on the publisher's own HTML pages, including any links
              that the service automatically adds. Processors MAY remove the
              markup and consider the note to be plain text.</t>

              <t hangText="permalink">The canonical URL for the status update.
              Represented as the value of the <spanx style="verb">href</spanx>
              attribute on an <spanx style="verb">atom:link</spanx> element
              with a <spanx style="verb">rel</spanx> value of <spanx
              style="verb">alternate</spanx> and a <spanx style="verb">type</spanx>
              value of <spanx style="verb">text/html</spanx>.</t>
            </list></t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="file" title="File">
          <t>The "file" Object type represents some document or other file
          with no additional machine-readable semantics.</t>

          <t>It is intended that this type be used as a base type for other
          Objects that manifest as files, so that additional semantics can be
          added while providing a fallback ability for clients that do not
          support the more specific Object type.</t>

          <t>The Object type URL for the "file" Object type is <spanx
          style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/file</spanx>.</t>

          <t>A file has the following properties:</t>

          <t><list style="hanging">
              <t hangText="associated file URL">The URL of the file described
              by this Object entry. The URL is represented as the value of the
              href attribute on an atom:link element with rel enclosure.
              Should there be multiple links with rel enclosure with different
              type attribute value, they are considered to be alternate
              representations of the file. Should there be multiple links with
              rel enclosure and with the <spanx>same</spanx> attribute value,
              the meaning is undefined for the file Object type and consumers
              MAY choose to present only the first of each supported type.</t>
            </list></t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="photo" title="Photo">
          <t>The "photo" object type represents a graphical still image.</t>

          <t>The object type URL for the "photo" Object type is <spanx
          style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/photo</spanx>.</t>

          <t>A photo has the following properties:</t>

          <t><list style="hanging">
              <t hangText="title">The title or short caption assigned to the
              photo by the author. Included as the content of the atom:title
              element. If the author has not provided a title, the publisher
              MAY synthesize a title e.g. from the image filename, or the
              publisher MAY include the atom:title element with no
              content.</t>

              <t hangText="thumbnail">The URL and metadata for a thumbnail
              version of the photo. The URL is represented as the value of the
              href attribute on an atom:link element with rel preview and a
              type of either image/jpeg, image/png or image/gif. Publishers
              SHOULD include media:width and media:height attributes on the
              atom:link element describing the dimensions of the linked image.
              Processors MAY ignore thumbnails that are of an inappropriate
              size for their user interface.</t>

              <t hangText="larger image">The URL and metadata for a larger,
              ideally full-size version of the photo intended for standalone
              viewing. The URL is represented as the value of the href
              attribute on an atom:link element with rel enclosure and a type
              of either image/jpeg, image/png or image/gif. Publishers SHOULD
              include media:width and media:height attributes on the atom:link
              element describing the dimensions of the linked image.</t>

              <t hangText="image page URL">The URL of a web page where the
              photo and the associated metadata can be viewed. Represented as
              the value of the href attribute on an atom:link element with a
              rel value of alternate and a type value of text/html.</t>

              <t hangText="description">The description or long caption
              assigned to the photo by the author. Included as the content of
              the media:description element as described in [AtomMedia]. If
              the author has not provided a description, this element SHOULD
              be omitted.</t>
            </list></t>

          <t>Publishers SHOULD include an atom:content element containing
          content that will present the photo and any necessary metadata to
          the user of a processor that is not media-aware. Media-aware
          processors SHOULD prefer the specific properties given above, but
          MAY use the content in preference in cases where the properties
          above are incomplete or unsuitable.</t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="photo-album" title="Photo Album">
          <t>The "photo album" object type represents a collection of
          images.</t>

          <t>The object type URL for the "photo album" object type is <spanx
          style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/photo-album</spanx>.</t>

          <t>The photo album object type has the following properties:</t>

          <t><list style="hanging">
              <t hangText="title">The title or short caption assigned to the
              album by the author. Included as the content of the atom:title
              element.</t>

              <t hangText="thumbnail">The URL and metadata for a preview image
              for the album. The URL is represented as the value of the href
              attribute on an atom:link element with rel preview and a type of
              either image/jpeg, image/png or image/gif. Publishers SHOULD
              include media:width and media:height attributes on the atom:link
              element describing the dimensions of the linked image.
              Processors MAY ignore thumbnails that are of an inappropriate
              size for their user interface.</t>

              <t hangText="album page URL">The URL of a web page where the
              photo album can be viewed. Represented as the value of the href
              attribute on an atom:link element with a rel value of alternate
              and a type value of text/html.</t>
            </list></t>
        </section>

        <section title="Playlist">
          <t>The "playlist" object type represents an ordered list of
          time-based media items, such as video and audio objects.</t>

          <t>The object type URL for the "playlist" object type is <spanx
          style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/playlist</spanx>.</t>

          <t>The playlist object type has the following properties:</t>

          <t><list style="hanging">
              <t hangText="title">The title or short caption assigned to the
              playlist by the author. Included as the content of the
              atom:title element.</t>

              <t hangText="thumbnail">The URL and metadata for a preview image
              for the playlist. The URL is represented as the value of the
              href attribute on an atom:link element with rel preview and a
              type of either image/jpeg, image/png or image/gif. Publishers
              SHOULD include media:width and media:height attributes on the
              atom:link element describing the dimensions of the linked image.
              Processors MAY ignore thumbnails that are of an inappropriate
              size for their user interface.</t>

              <t hangText="playlist page URL">The URL of a web page where the
              playlist can be viewed. Represented as the value of the href
              attribute on an atom:link element with a rel value of alternate
              and a type value of text/html.</t>
            </list></t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="video" title="Video">
          <t>The "video" Object type represents video content, which usually
          consists of a motion picture track and an audio track.</t>

          <t>The Object type URL for the "video" Object type is <spanx
          style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/video</spanx>.</t>

          <t>A video has the following properties:</t>

          <t><list style="hanging">
              <t hangText="title">The title or short caption assigned to the
              video by the author. Included as the content of the atom:title
              element. If the author has not provided a title, the publisher
              MAY synthesize a title e.g. from the video filename, or the
              publisher MAY include the atom:title element with no
              content.</t>

              <t hangText="thumbnail">The URL and metadata for a thumbnail
              version of a representative frame of the video. The URL is
              represented as the value of the href attribute on an atom:link
              element with rel preview and a type of either image/jpeg,
              image/png or image/gif. Publishers SHOULD include media:width
              and media:height attributes on the atom:link element describing
              the dimensions of the linked image. Processors MAY ignore
              thumbnails that are of an inappropriate size for their user
              interface.</t>

              <t hangText="video stream">The URL and metadata for the video
              content itself. The URL is represented as the value of the href
              attribute on an atom:link element with rel enclosure and a type
              that matches video/*. Publishers SHOULD include media:width and
              media:height attributes on the atom:link element describing the
              dimensions of the linked video, and SHOULD include a
              media:duration attribute giving the length of the video.</t>

              <t hangText="video page URL">The URL of a web page where the
              video and the associated metadata can be viewed. Represented as
              the value of the href attribute on an atom:link element with a
              rel value of alternate and a type value of text/html.</t>

              <t hangText="player applet">The URL and metadata for some kind
              of applet that will allow a user to view the video. The URL is
              represented as the value of the href attribute on an atom:link
              element with rel alternate and an appropriate type. Publishers
              SHOULD include media:width and media:height attributes on the
              atom:link element describing the ideal dimensions of the linked
              applet. If both a video page and player applet are included,
              publishers SHOULD include the video page link element first in
              document order for compatibility with legacy, non-activity feed
              consumers.</t>

              <t hangText="description">The description or long caption
              assigned to the video by the author. Included as the content of
              the atom:summary element as described in [AtomMedia]. If the
              author has not provided a description, this element SHOULD be
              omitted.</t>
            </list></t>

          <t>Publishers SHOULD include an atom:content element containing
          content that will present the video and any necessary metadata to
          the user of a processor that is not media-aware. Media-aware
          processors SHOULD prefer the specific properties given above, but
          MAY use the content in preference in cases where the properties
          above are incomplete or unsuitable.</t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="audio" title="Audio">
          <t>The "audio" Object type represents audio content.</t>

          <t>The Object type URL for the "audio" Object type is <spanx
          style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/audio</spanx>.</t>

          <t>An audio Object has the following properties:</t>

          <t><list style="hanging">
              <t hangText="title">The title or short caption assigned to the
              audio by the author. Included as the content of the atom:title
              element. If the author has not provided a title, the publisher
              MAY synthesize a title e.g. from the audio filename, or the
              publisher MAY include the atom:title element with no
              content.</t>

              <t hangText="audio stream">The URL and metadata for the audio
              content itself. The URL is represented as the value of the href
              attribute on an atom:link element with rel enclosure and a type
              that matches audio/*. Publishers SHOULD include a media:duration
              attribute on the atom:link element giving the length of the
              audio presentation in seconds.</t>

              <t hangText="audio page URL">The URL of a web page where the
              audio and the associated metadata can be accessed. Represented
              as the value of the href attribute on an atom:link element with
              a rel value of alternate and a type value of text/html.</t>

              <t hangText="player applet">The URL and metadata for some kind
              of applet that will allow a user to listen to the audio. The URL
              is represented as the value of the href attribute on an
              atom:link element with rel alternate and an appropriate type.
              Publishers SHOULD include media:width and media:height
              attributes on the atom:link element describing the ideal
              dimensions of the linked applet. If both an audio page and
              player applet are included, publishers SHOULD include the audio
              page link element first in document order for compatibility with
              legacy, non-activity feed consumers.</t>

              <t hangText="description">The description or long caption
              assigned to the audio by the author. Included as the content of
              the atom:summary element as described in [AtomMedia]. If the
              author has not provided a description, this element SHOULD be
              omitted.</t>
            </list></t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="bookmark" title="Bookmark">
          <t>The "bookmark" Object type represents a pointer to some URL --
          typically a web page. In most cases, a bookmark is specific to a
          given user and contains metadata chosen by that user. Bookmark
          Objects are similar in principle to the concept of bookmarks or
          favorites in a web browser. A bookmark represents a pointer to the
          URL, not the URL or the associated resource itself.</t>

          <t>When dealing with bookmarks it is important to note the
          distinction between the title, description, and URL of the bookmark
          itself and the title, content, and URL of the resource that is the
          target of the bookmark. In some implementations these MAY be the
          same, but bookmark managers often allow a user to edit the title and
          description of his or her own bookmarks to differ from the metadata
          on the target itself.</t>

          <t>Some implementations refer to this Object type as a "link". This
          specification uses the term "bookmark" to avoid confusion with the
          general concept of hyperlinks which apply to all Object types.</t>

          <t>Since bookmarks are often specific to a particular user, even
          though multiple users might have bookmarks pointing at the same
          resource, it is appropriate to use the "post" Verb to describe the
          publication of such a bookmark. The "mark as favorite" Verb SHOULD
          be used when a user flags another user's bookmark as being a
          favorite without creating his own bookmark, or when a user flags his
          own bookmark as being a favorite as a special classification within
          his own bookmark collection.</t>

          <t>The Object type URL for the "bookmark" Object type is <spanx
          style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/bookmark</spanx>.</t>

          <t>A bookmark has the following properties:</t>

          <t><list style="hanging">
              <t hangText="title">The title of the bookmark, as entered by the
              user who created the bookmark. Included as the content of the
              atom:title element. Publishers MAY use the title of the target
              resource as a default for this property where a user hasn't
              entered a customized value.</t>

              <t hangText="description">The description of the bookmark, as
              entered by the user who created the bookmark. Included as the
              content of the atom:summary element. If no description has been
              provided, publishers SHOULD omit this element.</t>

              <t hangText="target URL">The URL of the item that is the target
              of the bookmark. Represented as the value of the href attribute
              on an atom:link element with rel "related". An entry with this
              Object type MUST NOT include related links except for the
              purpose of representing the target URL.</t>

              <t hangText="bookmark page URL">The URL of a page that describes
              the bookmark. This URL is often specific to the user that
              published the bookmark. Represented as the value of the href
              attribute on an atom:link element with a rel value of alternate
              and a type value of text/html.</t>

              <t hangText="target title">The title of the item that is the
              target of the bookmark. Represented as the value of the title
              attribute on the atom:link element from which the target URL was
              obtained.</t>

              <t hangText="thumbnail">The URL and metadata for a thumbnail
              version of the page. The URL is represented as the value of the
              href attribute on an atom:link element with rel preview and a
              type of either image/jpeg, image/png or image/gif. Publishers
              SHOULD include media:width and media:height attributes on the
              atom:link element describing the dimensions of the linked image.
              Processors MAY ignore thumbnails that are of an inappropriate
              size for their user interface.</t>
            </list></t>

          <t>Publishers SHOULD include an atom:content element containing
          content that will present the bookmark to the user of a processor
          that does not have special support for bookmarks. Bookmark-aware
          processors SHOULD prefer the specific properties given above, but
          MAY use the content in preference in cases where the properties
          above are incomplete or unsuitable.</t>
        </section>

        <section title="Person">
          <t>The "person" Object type represents a user account. This is often
          a person, but might also be a company or fictitious character that
          is being represented by a user account.</t>

          <t>The object type URL for the "person" Object type is <spanx
          style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/person</spanx>.</t>

          <t>Where a particular person is referred to across multiple sources,
          the same value for <spanx style="verb">atom:id</spanx> SHOULD be
          used wherever possible. Two person objects in the same feed document
          with the same <spanx style="verb">atom:id</spanx> value can be
          considered by processors to be the same person. Processors MAY use
          other information to determine when two person objects refer to the
          same individual. A processor MUST NOT assume that two person objects
          with different values for <spanx style="verb">atom:id</spanx> refer
          to different people; different publishers may use different id
          values for the same individual.</t>

          <t>A person has the following properties:</t>

          <t><list style="hanging">
              <t hangText="display name">A name that can be used for a person
              in the user interface. This is often a name by which the
              individual is known in a given context; no restriction is placed
              on what kind of name may be used here. Included as the content
              of the atom:title element.</t>

              <t hangText="photo">The URL and metadata for an image that
              represents this user. The URL is represented as the value of the
              href attribute on an atom:link element with rel photo and a type
              of either image/jpeg, image/png, or image/gif. Publishers SHOULD
              include <spanx style="verb">media:width</spanx> and <spanx
              style="verb">media:height</spanx> attributes on the <spanx
              style="verb">atom:link</spanx> element describing the dimensions
              of the linked image. Processors MAY ignore photos that are of an
              inappropriate size for their user interface. Publishers MAY
              include several images of different sizes.</t>
            </list></t>
        </section>

        <section title="Service">
          <t>The "service" Object type represents a website, business, brand,
          or other entity that performs some kind of work for other entities,
          people, or services.</t>

          <t>The object type URL for the "service" Object type is <spanx
          style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/service</spanx>.</t>

          <t>Where a particular service is referred to across multiple
          sources, the same value for <spanx style="verb">atom:id</spanx>
          SHOULD be used wherever possible. Two service objects in the same
          feed document with the same <spanx style="verb">atom:id</spanx>
          value can be considered by processors to be the same service.
          Processors MAY use other information to determine when two service
          objects refer to the same service. A processor MUST NOT assume that
          two service objects with different values for <spanx style="verb">atom:id</spanx>
          refer to different services; different publishers may use different
          id values for the same service.</t>

          <t>A service has the following properties:</t>

          <t><list style="hanging">
              <t hangText="display name">A name that can be used for a service
              in the user interface. This is often a name by which the service
              is commonly known; no restriction is placed on what kind of name
              may be used here. Included as the content of the atom:title
              element.</t>

              <t hangText="icon">A small image with an aspect ratio of one
              (horizontal) to one (vertical) which SHOULD be suitable for
              presentation at a small size SHOULD be provided to represent the
              service.</t>

              <t hangText="photo">The URL and metadata for an image that
              represents this service. The URL is represented as the value of
              the href attribute on an <spanx style="verb">atom:link</spanx>
              element with rel photo and a type of either image/jpeg,
              image/png, or image/gif. Publishers SHOULD include <spanx
              style="verb">media:width</spanx> and <spanx style="verb">media:height</spanx>
              attributes on the <spanx style="verb">atom:link</spanx> element
              describing the dimensions of the linked image. Processors MAY
              ignore photos that are of an inappropriate size for their user
              interface. Publishers MAY include several images of different
              sizes.</t>
            </list></t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="group" title="Group">
          <t>The "group" Object type represents a social networking group. A
          group is a collection of people which people can join and leave.</t>

          <t>The Object type URL for the "group" Object type is <spanx
          style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/group</spanx>.</t>

          <t>A group has the following properties:</t>

          <t><list style="hanging">
              <t hangText="display name">A name that can be used for the group
              in the user interface. This is often a name chosen by the
              creator of the group. Included as the content of the atom:title
              element.</t>

              <t hangText="photo">The URL and metadata for an image that
              represents this group. The URL is represented as the value of
              the href attribute on an atom:link element with rel photo and a
              type of either image/jpeg, image/png or image/gif. Publishers
              SHOULD include media:width and media:height attributes on the
              atom:link element describing the dimensions of the linked image.
              Processors MAY ignore photos that are of an inappropriate size
              for their user interface. Publishers MAY include several images
              of different sizes.</t>
            </list></t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="place" title="Place">
          <t>The "place" object type represents a location on Earth.</t>

          <t>The object type URL for the "place" object type is <spanx
          style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/place</spanx>.</t>

          <t>A place has the following properties:</t>

          <t><list style="hanging">
              <t hangText="name">The name of the place. Included as the
              content of the atom:title element.</t>

              <t hangText="geographic coordinates">The latitude and longitude
              of the place as a point on Earth. Included via the <spanx
              style="verb">geo:point</spanx> element.</t>
            </list></t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="comment" title="Comment">
          <t>The "comment" object type represents a textual response to
          another object.</t>

          <t>The comment object type MUST NOT be used for other kinds of
          replies, such as video replies or reviews.</t>

          <t>If an object has no explicit type but the object element has a
          <spanx style="verb">thr:in-reply-to</spanx> element a consumer
          SHOULD consider that object to be a comment.</t>

          <t>The object type URL for the "comment" object type is <spanx
          style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/comment</spanx>.</t>

          <t>A comment has the following properties:</t>

          <t><list style="hanging">
              <t hangText="subject">The subject of the comment. Included as
              the content of the atom:title element. Many systems do not have
              the concept of a title or subject for a comment; such systems
              MUST include an atom:title element with no text content.
              Processors SHOULD refer to such comments as simply being "a
              comment", with appropriate localization, if they are to be
              described in a sentence.</t>

              <t hangText="content">The content of the comment. Included as
              the content of the atom:content element. Publishers SHOULD
              include any markup necessary to achieve a similar presentation
              to that on the publisher's own HTML pages, including any links
              that the service automatically adds. Processors MAY remove the
              markup and consider the comment to be plain text.</t>

              <t hangText="permalink">The canonical URL for the comment.
              Represented as the value of the <spanx style="verb">href</spanx>
              attribute on an <spanx style="verb">atom:link</spanx> element
              with a <spanx style="verb">rel</spanx> value of <spanx
              style="verb">alternate</spanx> and a <spanx style="verb">type</spanx>
              value of <spanx style="verb">text/html</spanx>. This URL may be
              the URL of the parent object with a fragment identifier
              appended, or a completely distinct URL.</t>
            </list></t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="review" title="Review">
          <t>The "review" object type represents a primarily prose-based
          commentary on another object.</t>

          <t>The object type URL for the "review" object type is <spanx
          style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/review</spanx>.</t>

          <t>A review has the following properties:</t>

          <t><list style="hanging">
              <t hangText="title">The title of the review. Included as the
              content of the atom:title element. Systems which produce reviews
              that do not have titles MUST include an atom:title element with
              no text content. Processors SHOULD refer to such comments as
              simply being "a review", with appropriate localization, if they
              are to be described in a sentence.</t>

              <t hangText="content">The content of the review. Included as the
              content of the atom:content element. Publishers SHOULD include
              any markup necessary to achieve a similar presentation to that
              on the publisher's own HTML pages, including any links that the
              service automatically adds.</t>

              <t hangText="permalink">The canonical URL for the review.
              Represented as the value of the <spanx style="verb">href</spanx>
              attribute on an <spanx style="verb">atom:link</spanx> element
              with a <spanx style="verb">rel</spanx> value of <spanx
              style="verb">alternate</spanx> and a <spanx style="verb">type</spanx>
              value of <spanx style="verb">text/html</spanx>. This URL may be
              the URL of the reviewed object with a fragment identifier
              appended, or a completely distinct URL.</t>

              <t hangText="reviewed object">The object that this review
              applies to. Included with a <spanx style="verb">thr:in-reply-to</spanx>
              element that refers to the <spanx style="verb">atom:id</spanx>
              value of the reviewed object.</t>

              <t hangText="rating">A rating attribute of the reviewed object.
              The rating is an optional field and is modeled after the rating
              attribute from the hReview microformat. Specifically, the rating
              may be defined as a fixed point integer [1.0-5.0] (with optional
              alternate worst (default:1.0) and/or best (default:5.0)), fixed
              point integers, or an explicit value.</t>
            </list></t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="list" title="List">
          <t>The list object type represents a collection of related
          objects.<list style="hanging">
              <t hangText="title">The name of the list. Included as the
              content of the atom:title element. Systems which produce lists
              that do not have titles MUST include an atom:title element with
              no text content.</t>

              <t hangText="summary">The description of the list. This
              description CAN be included.</t>

              <t hangText="permaLink">The canonical URL for the list.
              Represented as the value of the <spanx style="verb">href</spanx>
              attribute on an <spanx style="verb">atom:link</spanx> element
              with a <spanx style="verb">rel</spanx> value of <spanx
              style="verb">alternate</spanx> and a <spanx style="verb">type</spanx>
              value of <spanx style="verb">text/html</spanx>.</t>
            </list></t>

          <t></t>
        </section>
      </section>

      <section title="Base Activity Context Elements">
        <t>This specification defines an initial set of activity context
        elements that can be used with all activity entries. These provide
        orthogonal context information that can apply to all activities.</t>

        <section anchor="location" title="Location">
          <t>Location is a concept which can be used inside the atom:entry
          level, atom:author and activity:object. Location can be specified
          via geographic coordinates, a street address, a free-form location
          name or a combination of these. Geographic coordinates should be
          included as a geo:point element as described by the GeoRSS
          specification. Addresses should be included using a poco:address
          element defined at Portable Contacts specification. The entry level
          location represents the location of the author at the time the
          activity was performed. The author level location represents the
          primary location of the author. Finally, the location within other
          objects represents the physical location of those objects. All
          location fields are optional. For free form addresses use the
          poco:formatted field.</t>

          <t><xref target="location-poco"></xref></t>

          <t><figure anchor="location-poco" suppress-title="true"
              title="Location Example">
              <artwork><![CDATA[<entry>
  <id>tag:world:activity:1212121212121</id>
  <title>Rob liked Goldeberg's Deli</title>
  <author>
    <name>Rob Dolin</name>
    <id>tag:world:person:1212121212121</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://robdolin.com" />
    <poco:address>
      <poco:locality>Marina del Rey</poco:locality> 
      <poco:region>CA</poco:region> 
      <poco:postalCode>90292</poco:postalCode> 
      <poco:country>US</poco:country> 
    </poco:address>
  </author>
  <activity:object>
    <activity:object-type>http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/place</object-type>
    <id>tag:world:place:1212121212121</id>
    <title>Goldberg's Deli</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.deli.com" />
    <geo:point>33.9777 -118.4351</geo:point>
    <poco:address>
      <poco:streetAddress>14016 Bora Bora Way</poco:streetAddress>
      <poco:locality>Marina del Rey</poco:locality> 
      <poco:region>CA</poco:region>       
      <poco:postalCode>90292</poco:postalCode> 
      <poco:country>US</poco:country> 
    </poco:address>
  </activity:object>
  <geo:point>33.9777 -119.4351</geo:point>
  <activity:verb>http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/like</activity:verb>
</entry>]]></artwork>
            </figure></t>
        </section>

        <section title="new section">
          <t></t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="mood" title="Mood">
          <t>Mood describes the mood of the user when the activity was
          performed. This is usually collected via an extra field in the user
          interface used to perform the activity. For the purpose of this
          schema, a mood is a freeform, short mood keyword or phrase along
          with an optional mood icon image.</t>

          <t>Moods are included via a mood element in the namespace <spanx
          style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/context/</spanx>.</t>

          <t>The content of the mood element is the mood keyword or
          phrase.</t>

          <t>The mood element may have an optional <spanx style="verb">icon</spanx>
          attribute which contains the URL of a mood icon image. The mood icon
          image SHOULD be small and appropriate to be displayed alongside the
          mood keyword at a normal text size.</t>
        </section>
      </section>

      <section anchor="replies" title="Replies">
        <t>Most social applications have a concept of "comments", "replies" or
        "responses" to social Objects. In many cases these are simple text
        messages, but any Object can in practice be a reply.</t>

        <t>A text-only reply SHOULD be represented using the comment object
        type as described in <xref target="comment"></xref>. Replies of other
        types MUST carry the appropriate type and MUST NOT carry the comment
        object type.</t>

        <t>Replies, regardless of object type, SHOULD be represented using the
        <spanx style="verb">thr:in-reply-to</spanx> element defined by <xref
        target="RFC4685"></xref>. Publishers SHOULD also, if available,
        include metadata about the item being replied to using the mechanisms
        defined in <xref target="atomcommentmeta-00"></xref>.</t>

        <t>The act of posting a reply is represented by the post Verb as with
        "top-level" Objects.</t>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section title="Event Schema">
      <t>The event schema provides a vocabulary that is useful in applications
      that use real-world events and meetings as social objects.</t>

      <section title="Event Verbs">
        <section anchor="rsvp-yes" title="Positive RSVP">
          <t>The "positive RSVP" verb indicates that the actor has made a
          positive RSVP for the object. This specification only defines the
          meaning of this verb when its object is an event (see <xref
          target="event"></xref>), though implementors SHOULD be prepared to
          handle other object types as meaning MAY be provided by extension
          specifications.</t>

          <t>The use of this Verb is only appropriate when the RSVP was
          created by an explicit action by the actor. It is not appropriate to
          use this verb when a user has been added as an attendee by an event
          organiser or administrator.</t>

          <t>The verb URI for the "positive RSVP" Verb is <spanx style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/rsvp-yes</spanx>.</t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="rsvp-maybe" title="Possible RSVP">
          <t>The "possible RSVP" verb indicates that the actor has made a
          possible RSVP for the object. This specification only defines the
          meaning of this verb when its object is an event (see <xref
          target="event"></xref>), though implementors SHOULD be prepared to
          handle other object types as meaning MAY be provided by extension
          specifications.</t>

          <t>The use of this Verb is only appropriate when the RSVP was
          created by an explicit action by the actor. It is not appropriate to
          use this verb when a user has been added as an attendee by an event
          organiser or administrator.</t>

          <t>The verb URI for the "possible RSVP" Verb is <spanx style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/rsvp-maybe</spanx>.</t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="rsvp-no" title="Negative RSVP">
          <t>The "negative RSVP" verb indicates that the actor has made a
          negative RSVP for the object. This specification only defines the
          meaning of this verb when its object is an event (see <xref
          target="event"></xref>), though implementors SHOULD be prepared to
          handle other object types as meaning MAY be provided by extension
          specifications.</t>

          <t>The use of this Verb is only appropriate when the RSVP was
          created by an explicit action by the actor. It is not appropriate to
          use this verb when a user has been added as an attendee by an event
          organiser or administrator.</t>

          <t>The verb URI for the "negative RSVP" Verb is <spanx style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/rsvp-no</spanx>.</t>
        </section>
      </section>

      <section title="Event Object Types">
        <section anchor="event" title="Event">
          <t>The "event" object type represents an event that occurs in a
          certain place during a particular interval of time.</t>

          <t>The object type URL for the "event" object type is <spanx
          style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/event</spanx>.</t>

          <t>An event has the following properties:</t>

          <t><list style="hanging">
              <t hangText="name">The name of the event as provided by its
              organiser. Included as the content of the atom:title
              element.</t>

              <t hangText="start date and time">The date and time that the
              event begins. Included via a cal:dtstart element as defined in
              xCal.</t>

              <t hangText="end date and time">The date and time that the event
              ends. Included via a cal:dtend element as defined in xCal.</t>

              <t hangText="summary">A short description of the event as
              provided by its organiser. Included as the content of the
              atom:summary element.</t>
            </list></t>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section title="Music Schema">
      <t>The music schema provides a vocabulary that is useful in applications
      that use music, musicians and albums as social objects.</t>

      <section title="Music Object Types">
        <section anchor="song" title="Song">
          <t>The "song" Object type represents a song or a recording of a
          song.</t>

          <t>Objects of type Song might contain information about the song or
          recording, or they might contain some representation of the
          recording itself. In the latter case, the song SHOULD also be
          annotated with the "audio" object type as described in <xref
          target="audio"></xref> and use its properties. This type should only
          be used when the publisher can guarantee that the object is a song
          rather than merely a generic audio stream.</t>

          <t>The Object type URL for the "song" Object type is <spanx
          style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/song</spanx>.</t>

          <t>A song has the following properties:</t>

          <t><list style="hanging">
              <t hangText="title">The title of the song. Included as the
              content of the atom:title element.</t>
            </list></t>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </middle>

  <back>
    <references title="Normative References">
      <reference anchor="RFC4287">
        <front>
          <title>The Atom Syndication Format</title>

          <author>
            <organization></organization>
          </author>

          <date />
        </front>
      </reference>

      <reference anchor="RFC2119">
        <front>
          <title>RFC 2119</title>

          <author>
            <organization></organization>
          </author>

          <date />
        </front>
      </reference>

      <reference anchor="RFC3987">
        <front>
          <title>Internationalized Resource Identifiers (IRIs)</title>

          <author>
            <organization></organization>
          </author>

          <date />
        </front>
      </reference>

      <reference anchor="RFC4685">
        <front>
          <title>Atom Threading Extensions</title>

          <author fullname="James M. Snell" initials="J. M." surname="Snell">
            <organization></organization>
          </author>

          <date month="September" year="2006" />
        </front>
      </reference>

      <reference anchor="atomcommentmeta-00">
        <front>
          <title>Atom Comment Metadata Extensions</title>

          <author fullname="Martin Atkins" initials="M." surname="Atkins">
            <organization></organization>
          </author>

          <date />
        </front>
      </reference>

      <reference anchor="hreview">
        <front>
          <title>The hReview Microformat</title>

          <author>
            <organization>microformats community</organization>
          </author>

          <date />
        </front>
      </reference>
    </references>

    <section title="Acknowledgements">
      <t>...</t>
    </section>
  </back>
</rfc>
