<?xml version="1.0" encoding="US-ASCII"?>
<!DOCTYPE rfc SYSTEM "rfc2629.dtd">
<?rfc toc="yes"?>
<?rfc tocompact="yes"?>
<?rfc tocdepth="3"?>
<?rfc tocindent="yes"?>
<?rfc symrefs="yes"?>
<?rfc sortrefs="yes"?>
<?rfc comments="yes"?>
<?rfc inline="yes"?>
<?rfc compact="yes"?>
<?rfc subcompact="no"?>
<?rfc private="Draft"?>
<rfc category="exp" docName="atomactivity-00" ipr="none">
  <front>
    <title abbrev="AtomActivitySchema">Atom Activity Base Schema
    (Draft)</title>

    <author fullname="Martin Atkins" initials="M." surname="Atkins">
      <organization>Six Apart Ltd</organization>
    </author>

    <date />

    <abstract>
      <t>This document presents a base set of object types and verbs for use
      with Atom Activity Extensions.</t>
    </abstract>

    <note title="Requirements Language">
      <t>The key words "MUST", "MUST NOT", "REQUIRED", "SHALL", "SHALL NOT",
      "SHOULD", "SHOULD NOT", "RECOMMENDED", "MAY", and "OPTIONAL" in this
      document are to be interpreted as described in <xref
      target="RFC2119">RFC 2119</xref>.</t>
    </note>
  </front>

  <middle>
    <section title="Introduction">
      <t>This document presents a base set of object types and verbs for use
      with Atom Activity Extensions..</t>
    </section>

    <section title="Notational Conventions">
      <t>In this document, the following namespace prefixes are used for the
      given namespace URI from the referenced specification:</t>

      <texttable>
        <ttcol>Alias</ttcol>

        <ttcol>Namespace URI</ttcol>

        <ttcol>Specification</ttcol>

        <c><spanx style="verb">atom:</spanx></c>

        <c><spanx style="verb">http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom</spanx></c>

        <c><xref target="RFC4287">The Atom Syndication Format</xref></c>

        <c><spanx style="verb">thr:</spanx></c>

        <c><spanx style="verb">http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0</spanx></c>

        <c><xref target="RFC4685">Atom Threading Extensions</xref></c>

        <c><spanx style="verb">activity:</spanx></c>

        <c><spanx style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/</spanx></c>

        <c>Atom Activity Extensions</c>

        <c><spanx style="verb">media:</spanx></c>

        <c><spanx style="verb">http://purl.org/syndication/atommedia</spanx></c>

        <c>Atom Media Extensions</c>
      </texttable>

      <t>Note that the choices of namespace prefix are arbitrary and not
      semantically significant.</t>

      <t>This specification uses a shorthand form of terms from the XML
      Infoset [W3C.REC-xml-infoset-20040204]. The phrase "Information Item" is
      omitted when naming Element and Attribute Information Items. Therefore,
      when this specification uses the term "element," it is referring to an
      Element Information Item in Infoset terms. Likewise, when this
      specification uses the term "attribute," it is referring to an Attribute
      Information Item.</t>

      <t>This specification allows the use of IRIs [RFC3987]. Every URI
      [RFC3986] is also an IRI, so a URI may be used wherever an IRI is named.
      When an IRI that is not also a URI is given for dereferencing, it MUST
      be mapped to a URI using the steps in Section 3.1 of [RFC3987]. When an
      IRI is serving as an identifier, it MUST NOT be so mapped.</t>

      <t>Some sections of this specification are illustrated with a non-
      normative RELAX NG Compact schema [RELAXNG]. In those sections, this
      specification uses the atomCommonAttributes, atomMediaType, and atomURI
      patterns, defined in [RFC4287].</t>

      <t>However, the text of this specification provides the sole definition
      of conformance.</t>

      <t>This specification uses "the Atom specification" to refer to <xref
      target="RFC4287"></xref>, and "the AtomActivity specification" to refer
      to [insert xref here].</t>
    </section>

    <section title="Base Verbs">
      <section title="Post">
        <t>The "post" verb is described in section 8 of the AtomActivity
        specification. It is only referenced here for completeness.</t>
      </section>

      <section title="Mark as Favorite">
        <t>The "Mark as Favorite" verb indicates that the actor marked the
        object as an item of special interest. Often objects so marked appear
        in a collection of such objects which may be published as a feed of
        entries annotated with this verb.</t>

        <t>The verb URI for the "Mark as Favorite" verb is <spanx
        style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/favorite/</spanx>.</t>

        <t>This verb has no additional properties beyond the basic activity
        properties described in the AtomActivity specification.</t>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section title="Base Object Types">
      <section title="Weblog Entry">
        <t>The "weblog entry" object type indicates that the object is an
        entry that has been posted in a weblog, or some similar construct such
        as an online journal.</t>

        <t>Weblog entries generally consist of paragraphs of text, in some
        cases incorporating embedded media such as photos and inline
        hyperlinks to other resources.</t>

        <t>The object type URL for the "weblog entry" object type is <spanx
        style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/blog-entry/</spanx>.</t>

        <t>A weblog entry has the following properties:</t>

        <t><list style="hanging">
            <t hangText="title">The title of the entry. Included as the
            content of the atom:title element. If the entry does not have a
            title, this element MUST be included with empty content</t>

            <t hangText="summary">A short excerpt of the body content that
            gives an introduction to or a summary of the full content; if the
            entry does not have a summary, this element should be omitted.</t>

            <t hangText="body">The main body content of the entry. Included as
            the content of the atom:content element</t>

            <t hangText="permalink">The canonical URL for the entry.
            Represented as the value of the <spanx style="verb">href</spanx>
            attribute on an <spanx style="verb">atom:link</spanx> element with
            a <spanx style="verb">rel</spanx> value of <spanx style="verb">alternate</spanx>
            and a <spanx style="verb">type</spanx> value of <spanx
            style="verb">text/html</spanx>.</t>
          </list></t>
      </section>

      <section title="Note">
        <t>The "note" object type represents short notes or status updates.
        This object type is intended for use in "micro-blogging" and in
        systems where users are invited to publish a timestamped "status".</t>

        <t>A note is similar in structure to a weblog entry, but it does not
        have a title and its body tends to be shorter. Applications will often
        display the entire content of a note in an activity stream UI, whereas
        they may display only the title or the title and summary for a weblog
        entry.</t>

        <t>The object type URL for the "note" object type is <spanx
        style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note/</spanx>.</t>

        <t>A note has the following properties:</t>

        <t><list style="hanging">
            <t hangText="content">The content of the note. Included as the
            content of the atom:content element. Publishers SHOULD include any
            markup necessary to achieve a similar presentation to that on the
            publisher's own HTML pages, including any links that the service
            automatically adds. Processors MAY remove the markup and consider
            the note to be plain text.</t>

            <t hangText="permalink">The canonical URL for the note.
            Represented as the value of the <spanx style="verb">href</spanx>
            attribute on an <spanx style="verb">atom:link</spanx> element with
            a <spanx style="verb">rel</spanx> value of <spanx style="verb">alternate</spanx>
            and a <spanx style="verb">type</spanx> value of <spanx
            style="verb">text/html</spanx>.</t>
          </list></t>

        <t><spanx style="strong">TODO:</spanx> Figure out how to handle the
        notes published by Facebook and Plaxo that are full sentences that
        always start with the name of the actor.</t>
      </section>

      <section title="Photo">
        <t>The "photo" object type represents a graphical still image which is
        often, but not always, a photograph. Some users publish
        non-photographic images such as drawings into photo galleries, so this
        specification does not attempt to create an artificial
        distinction.</t>

        <t>The object type URL for the "photo" object type is <spanx
        style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/photo/</spanx>.</t>

        <t>A photo has the following properties:</t>

        <t><list style="hanging">
            <t hangText="title">The title or short caption assigned to the
            photo by the author. Included as the content of the atom:title
            element. If the author has not provided a title, the publisher may
            synthesize a title e.g. from the image filename, or the publisher
            may include the atom:title element with no content.</t>

            <t hangText="thumbnail">The URL and metadata for a thumbnail
            version of the photo. The URL is represented as the value of the
            href attribute on an atom:link element with rel preview and a type
            of either image/jpeg, image/png or image/gif. Publishers SHOULD
            include media:width and media:height attributes on the atom:link
            element describing the dimensions of the linked image. Processors
            MAY ignore thumbnails that are of an inappropriate size for their
            user interface.</t>

            <t hangText="larger image">The URL and metadata for a larger,
            ideally full-size version of the photo intended for standalone
            viewing. The URL is represented as the value of the href attribute
            on an atom:link element with rel enclosure and a type of either
            image/jpeg, image/png or image/gif. Publishers SHOULD include
            media:width and media:height attributes on the atom:link element
            describing the dimensions of the linked image.</t>

            <t hangText="photo page URL">The URL of a web page where the photo
            and the associated metadata can be viewed. Represented as the
            value of the href attribute on an atom:link element with a rel
            value of alternate and a type value of text/html.</t>

            <t hangText="time and date the photo was taken">The time and date
            when the photo was taken, as opposed to when it was posted. This
            information is often determined automatically by the
            photographer's camera, but may be inaccurate due to an incorrect
            clock in the camera. <spanx style="strong">TODO:</spanx> Figure
            out how to publish this. There doesn't seem to be any
            well-deployed standard.</t>

            <t hangText="description">The description or long caption assigned
            to the photo by the author. Included as the content of the
            media:description element as described in [AtomMedia]. If the
            author has not provided a description, this element SHOULD be
            omitted.</t>
          </list></t>

        <t>Publishers SHOULD include an atom:content element containing
        content that will present the photo and any necessary metadata to the
        user of a processor that is not media-aware. Media-aware processors
        SHOULD prefer the specific properties given above, but MAY use the
        content in preference in cases where the properties above are
        incomplete or unsuitable.</t>
      </section>

      <section title="Video">
        <t>The "video" object type represents video content, which usually
        consists of a motion picture track and an audio track.</t>

        <t>The object type URL for the "video" object type is <spanx
        style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/video/</spanx>.</t>

        <t>A video has the following properties:</t>

        <t><list style="hanging">
            <t hangText="title">The title or short caption assigned to the
            video by the author. Included as the content of the atom:title
            element. If the author has not provided a title, the publisher may
            synthesize a title e.g. from the video filename, or the publisher
            may include the atom:title element with no content.</t>

            <t hangText="thumbnail">The URL and metadata for a thumbnail
            version of a representative frame of the video. The URL is
            represented as the value of the href attribute on an atom:link
            element with rel preview and a type of either image/jpeg,
            image/png or image/gif. Publishers SHOULD include media:width and
            media:height attributes on the atom:link element describing the
            dimensions of the linked image. Processors MAY ignore thumbnails
            that are of an inappropriate size for their user interface.</t>

            <t hangText="video stream">The URL and metadata for the video
            content itself. The URL is represented as the value of the href
            attribute on an atom:link element with rel enclosure and a type
            that matches video/*. Publishers SHOULD include media:width and
            media:height attributes on the atom:link element describing the
            dimensions of the linked video, and SHOULD include a
            media:duration attribute giving the length of the video.</t>

            <t hangText="video page URL">The URL of a web page where the video
            and the associated metadata can be viewed. Represented as the
            value of the href attribute on an atom:link element with a rel
            value of alternate and a type value of text/html.</t>

            <t hangText="player applet">The URL and metadata for some kind of
            applet that will allow a user to view the video. The URL is
            represented as the value of the href attribute on an atom:link
            element with rel alternate and an appropriate type. Publishers
            SHOULD include media:width and media:height attributes on the
            atom:link element describing the ideal dimensions of the linked
            applet. If both a video page and player applet are included,
            publishers SHOULD include the video page link element first in
            document order for compatibility with legacy, non-activity feed
            consumers.</t>

            <t hangText="description">The description or long caption assigned
            to the video by the author. Included as the content of the
            media:description element as described in [AtomMedia]. If the
            author has not provided a description, this element SHOULD be
            omitted.</t>
          </list></t>

        <t>Publishers SHOULD include an atom:content element containing
        content that will present the video and any necessary metadata to the
        user of a processor that is not media-aware. Media-aware processors
        SHOULD prefer the specific properties given above, but MAY use the
        content in preference in cases where the properties above are
        incomplete or unsuitable.</t>
      </section>

      <section title="Bookmark">
        <t>The "bookmark" object type represents a pointer to some URL, which
        is usually a web page. In most cases, a bookmark is specific to a
        given user, and contains metadata chosen by that user. Bookmark
        objects are similar in principle to the concept of bookmarks or
        favorites in a web browser.</t>

        <t>When dealing with bookmarks it is important to note the distinction
        between the title, description and URL of the bookmark itself and the
        title, content and URL of the resource that is the target of the
        bookmark. In some implementations these may be the same, but bookmark
        managers often allow a user to edit the title and description of his
        own bookmarks to differ from the metadata on the target itself.</t>

        <t>Some implementations refer to this object type as a "link". This
        specification uses the term "bookmark" to avoid confusion with the
        general concept of hyperlinks which apply to all object types.</t>

        <t>Since bookmarks are often specific to a particular user, even
        though multiple users might have bookmarks pointing at the same
        resource, it is appropriate to use the "post" verb to describe the
        publication of such a bookmark. The "mark as favorite" verb SHOULD be
        used when a user flags another user's bookmark as being a favorite
        without creating his own copy of the favorite, or when a user flags
        his own bookmark as being a favorite as a special classification
        within his bookmark collection.</t>

        <t>The object type URL for the "bookmark" object type is <spanx
        style="verb">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/bookmark/</spanx>.</t>

        <t>A bookmark has the following properties:</t>

        <t><list style="hanging">
            <t hangText="title">The title of the bookmark, as entered by the
            user who created the bookmark. Included as the content of the
            atom:title element. Publishers MAY use the title of the target
            resource as a default for this property where a user hasn't
            entered a customized value.</t>

            <t hangText="description">The description of the bookmark, as
            entered by the user who created the bookmark. Included as the
            content of the atom:summary element. If no description has been
            provided, publishers SHOULD omit this element.</t>

            <t hangText="target URL">The URL of the item that is the target of
            the bookmark. Represented as the value of the href attribute on an
            atom:link element with rel "related". An entry with this object
            type MUST NOT include related links except for the purpose of
            representing the target URL.</t>

            <t hangText="bookmark page URL">The URL of a page that describes
            the bookmark. This URL is often specific to the user that
            published the bookmark. Represented as the value of the href
            attribute on an atom:link element with a rel value of alternate
            and a type value of text/html.</t>

            <t hangText="target title">The title of the item that is the
            target of the bookmark. Represented as the value of the title
            attribute on the atom:link element from which the target URL was
            obtained.</t>

            <t hangText="thumbnail">The URL and metadata for a thumbnail
            version of the page. The URL is represented as the value of the
            href attribute on an atom:link element with rel preview and a type
            of either image/jpeg, image/png or image/gif. Publishers SHOULD
            include media:width and media:height attributes on the atom:link
            element describing the dimensions of the linked image. Processors
            MAY ignore thumbnails that are of an inappropriate size for their
            user interface.</t>
          </list></t>

        <t>Publishers SHOULD include an atom:content element containing
        content that will present the bookmark to the user of a processor that
        does not have special support for bookmarks. Bookmark-aware processors
        SHOULD prefer the specific properties given above, but MAY use the
        content in preference in cases where the properties above are
        incomplete or unsuitable.</t>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section title="Comments and Responses">
      <t>Most social applications have a concept of "comments", "replies" or
      "responses" to social objects. In many cases these are simple text
      messages, but any object can in practice be a reply.</t>

      <t>This specification does not define an object type for a comment nor a
      verb for posting a comment. This is because an item being in response to
      another item is orthogonal to its type, and "posting a comment" is of
      course simply a "post" action.</t>

      <t>Therefore replies SHOULD be represented using the <spanx
      style="verb">thr:in-reply-to</spanx> element defined by <xref
      target="RFC4685"></xref>. Publishers SHOULD also, if available, include
      metadata about the item being replied to using the mechanisms defined in
      [CommentMetadataExtension].</t>

      <t>The act of posting a comment is represented by the post verb as with
      "top-level" objects.</t>

      <t>A simple text comment should in most cases not have an object type.
      If the reply is in fact an object such as a video, it SHOULD be
      annotated with an appropriate object type.</t>

      <t>Many systems do not have the concept of a title or subject for a
      comment; such systems MUST include an atom:title element with no text
      content. Processors SHOULD refer to such comments as simply being "a
      comment" if they are to be described in a sentence.</t>

      <t><spanx style="strong">FIXME:</spanx> Must figure out how Trackback
      and friends are represented. An entry that "tracks back" to another is
      effectively a reply, but there are questions about who publishes this
      relationship (the responder or the original poster -- or indeed both)
      and how exactly the entry metadata is represented in a feed.</t>
    </section>

    <section title="Security Considerations">
      <t>[TODO: Write some more here.]</t>
    </section>

    <section title="IANA Considerations">
      <t>None.</t>
    </section>
  </middle>

  <back>
    <references title="Normative References">
      <reference anchor="RFC4287">
        <front>
          <title>The Atom Syndication Format</title>

          <author>
            <organization></organization>
          </author>

          <date />
        </front>
      </reference>

      <reference anchor="RFC2119">
        <front>
          <title>RFC 2119</title>

          <author>
            <organization></organization>
          </author>

          <date />
        </front>
      </reference>

      <reference anchor="RFC3987">
        <front>
          <title>Internationalized Resource Identifiers (IRIs)</title>

          <author>
            <organization></organization>
          </author>

          <date />
        </front>
      </reference>

      <reference anchor="RFC4685">
        <front>
          <title>Atom Threading Extensions</title>

          <author fullname="James M. Snell" initials="J. M." surname="Snell">
            <organization></organization>
          </author>

          <date month="September" year="2006" />
        </front>
      </reference>
    </references>

    <section title="Acknowledgements">
      <t>...</t>
    </section>
  </back>
</rfc>
