<?xml version="1.0" encoding="US-ASCII"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='./rfc2629.xslt' ?>
<!DOCTYPE rfc SYSTEM "rfc2629.dtd">
<?rfc toc="yes"?>
<?rfc tocompact="yes"?>
<?rfc tocdepth="3"?>
<?rfc tocindent="yes"?>
<?rfc symrefs="yes"?>
<?rfc sortrefs="yes"?>
<?rfc comments="yes"?>
<?rfc inline="yes"?>
<?rfc compact="yes"?>
<?rfc subcompact="no"?>
<rfc category="exp" docName="activity-schema-01" ipr="none">
  <front>
    <title abbrev="ActivitySchema">Activity Base Schema (Draft)</title>

    <author fullname="James M Snell" initials="J.M." surname="Snell">
      <organization>IBM</organization>
    </author>

    <author fullname="Martin Atkins" initials="M." surname="Atkins">
      <organization>SAY Media</organization>
    </author>

    <author fullname="David Recordon" initials="D." surname="Recordon">
      <organization>Six Apart, Facebook</organization>
    </author>

    <author fullname="Chris Messina" initials="C." surname="Messina">
      <organization>Citizen Agency, Google</organization>
    </author>

    <author fullname="Monica Keller" initials="M." surname="Keller">
      <organization>MySpace, Facebook</organization>
    </author>

    <author fullname="Ari Steinberg" initials="A." surname="Steinberg">
      <organization>Facebook</organization>
    </author>

    <author fullname="Rob Dolin" initials="R." surname="Dolin">
      <organization>Microsoft</organization>
    </author>

    <date />

    <abstract>
      <t>This document presents a base set of Object types and Verbs for use
      with Activity Streams.</t>
    </abstract>

    <note title="Requirements Language">
      <t>The key words "MUST", "MUST NOT", "REQUIRED", "SHALL", "SHALL NOT",
      "SHOULD", "SHOULD NOT", "RECOMMENDED", "MAY", and "OPTIONAL" in this
      document are to be interpreted as described in <xref
      target="RFC2119">RFC 2119</xref>.</t>
    </note>
  </front>

  <middle>
    <section title="Introduction">
      <t>This document presents a base set of object types and verbs for use
      with Activity Streams.</t>
    </section>

    <section title="Notational Conventions">
      <t>This specification allows the use of IRIs [RFC3987]. Every URI
      [RFC3986] is also an IRI, so a URI MAY be used wherever an IRI is named.
      When an IRI that is not also a URI is given for dereferencing, it MUST
      be mapped to a URI using the steps in Section 3.1 of [RFC3987]. When an
      IRI is serving as an identifier, it MUST NOT be so mapped.</t>
    </section>

      <section anchor="verbs" title="Verbs">
      
        <texttable>
          <ttcol align="left" width="15%">Verb</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left">Description</ttcol>
      
          <c><spanx style="verb">add</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has added the object to the target. 
          For instance, adding a photo to an album.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">cancel</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has canceled the object. For 
          instance, canceling a calendar event.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">checkin</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has checked-in to the object. For 
          instance, a person checking-in to a Place.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">delete</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has deleted the object. This 
          implies, but does not require, the permanent destruction of the 
          object.</c>
      
          <c><spanx style="verb">favorite</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor marked the object as an item of 
          special interest.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">follow</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor began following the activity of the 
          object. In most cases, the object will be a 
          <xref target="person">Person</xref>, but it can
          potentially be of any type that can sensibly generate activity.
          Processors MAY ignore (silently drop) successive identical "follow" 
          activities.</c>
                
          <c><spanx style="verb">give</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor is giving an object to the target.
          Examples include one person giving a <spanx style="verb">badge</spanx>
          object to another person. The <spanx style="verb">object</spanx>
          identifies the object being given. The <spanx style="verb">target</spanx>
          identifies the receiver.</c>
        
          <c><spanx style="verb">ignore</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has ignored the object. For instance, 
          this verb may be used when an actor has ignored a friend request, 
          in which case the object may be the <spanx style="verb">request-friend</spanx>
          activity.</c>
        
          <c><spanx style="verb">invite</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has invited the object, typically a 
          person object, to join or participate in the object described by
          the <spanx style="verb">target</spanx>. The target could, for instance,
          be an event, group or a service.</c>
        
          <c><spanx style="verb">join</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has become a member of the object. This 
          specification only defines the meaning of this verb
          when its object is a <xref target="group">group</xref>, though
          implementors SHOULD be prepared to handle other Object types as
          meaning MAY be provided by extension specifications. Processors 
          MAY ignore (silently drop) successive identical "join" activities.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">leave</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has left the object. For instance, 
          a Person leaving a Group or checking-out of a Place.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">like</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor marked the object as an item of special 
          interest. The "like" verb is considered to be an alias of "favorite". 
          The two verb are semantically identical.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">make-friend</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates the creation of a friendship that is reciprocated by 
          the object. Since this verb implies an activity on the part of its object,
          processors MUST NOT accept activities with this verb unless they are
          able to verify through some external means that there is in fact a
          reciprocated connection. For example, a processor may have received
          a guarantee from a particular publisher that the publisher will only
          use this Verb in cases where a reciprocal relationship exists.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">play</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor spent some time enjoying the object. 
          For example, if the object is a video this indicates that the subject 
          watched all or part of the video.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">receive</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor is receiving an object.
          Examples include a person receiving a <spanx style="verb">badge</spanx>
          object. The <spanx style="verb">object</spanx>
          identifies the object being received.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">remove</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has removed the object from the target.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">remove-friend</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has removed the object from the collection
          of friends.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">request-friend</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates the creation of a friendship that has not yet been reciprocated by 
          the object.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">rsvp-maybe</spanx></c> 
          <c>The "possible RSVP" verb indicates that the actor has made a
          possible RSVP for the object. This specification only defines the
          meaning of this verb when its object is an event (see <xref
          target="event"></xref>), though implementors SHOULD be prepared to
          handle other object types as meaning MAY be provided by extension
          specifications. The use of this verb is only appropriate when the RSVP was
          created by an explicit action by the actor. It is not appropriate to
          use this verb when a user has been added as an attendee by an event
          organiser or administrator.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">rsvp-no</spanx></c>
          <c>The "negative RSVP" verb indicates that the actor has made a
          negative RSVP for the object. This specification only defines the
          meaning of this verb when its object is an event (see <xref
          target="event"></xref>), though implementors SHOULD be prepared to
          handle other object types as meaning MAY be provided by extension
          specifications. The use of this verb is only appropriate when the RSVP was
          created by an explicit action by the actor. It is not appropriate to
          use this verb when a user has been added as an attendee by an event
          organiser or administrator.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">rsvp-yes</spanx></c>
          <c>The "positive RSVP" verb indicates that the actor has made a
          positive RSVP for an object. This specification only defines the
          meaning of this verb when its object is an event (see <xref
          target="event" />), though implementors SHOULD be prepared to
          handle other object types as meaning MAY be provided by extension
          specifications. The use of this verb is only appropriate when the RSVP was
          created by an explicit action by the actor. It is not appropriate to
          use this verb when a user has been added as an attendee by an event
          organiser or administrator.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">save</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has called out the object as being of 
          interest primarily to him- or herself. Though this action MAY be 
          shared publicly, the implication is that the object has been saved 
          primarily for the actor's own benefit rather than to show it to 
          others as would be indicated by the "share" verb.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">share</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has called out the object to readers. 
          In most cases, the actor did not create the object being shared, 
          but is instead drawing attention to it.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">stop-following</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has stopped following the object.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">tag</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has identified the presence of a target 
          inside another object. For example, the actor may have specified that 
          a particular user appears in a photo. The target of the "tag" verb 
          gives the object in which the tag has been added. For example, if a 
          user appears in a photo, the <spanx style="verb">object</spanx> 
          is the user and the <spanx style="verb">target</spanx> is the photo.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">unfavorite</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has removed the object from the collection
          of favorited items.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">unlike</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has removed the object from the collection
          of liked items.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">unsave</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has removed the object from the collection
          of saved items.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">update</spanx></c>
          <c>The "update" verb indicates that the actor has modified the
          object. Implementors SHOULD use verbs such as <spanx style="verb">post</spanx>
          where the actor is adding new items to a <xref target="collection">collection</xref> or 
          similar. Update is reserved for modifications to existing objects 
          or data such as changing a user's profile information.</c>
        </texttable>

      </section>

      <section anchor="object-types" title="Object Types">
        <section anchor="article" title="Article">
          <t>The "article" object type indicates that the object is an
          article, such as a news article, a knowledge base entry, or other
          similar construct. Such objects generally consist of paragraphs 
          of text, in some cases incorporating embedded media such as photos 
          and inline hyperlinks to other resources.</t>

          <t>At a minimum, an article object has the following properties:</t>

          <texttable>
          <ttcol align="left" width="15%">Property</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left" width="21%">Value</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left">Description</ttcol>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">author</spanx></c>
          <c>Activity Object</c>
          <c>Activity Object, typically using the "person" object type, 
          responsible for the creation of the article. If the article 
          object appears within an activity, and the 
          <spanx style="verb">author</spanx> of the article
          is the <spanx style="verb">actor</spanx> for the activity, the 
          <spanx style="verb">author</spanx> property MAY be omitted</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">content</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional main body content represented as a fragment of HTML. </c>
                              
          <c><spanx style="verb">displayName</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The natural-language, human-readable and plain-text title of the 
          article.HTML markup MUST NOT be included</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">id</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The unique identifier for the article.</c>
                    
          <c><spanx style="verb">published</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional time the article was created in the form of an 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/> "date-time".</c>
         
          <c><spanx style="verb">summary</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>Optional short, natural-language, human-readable snippet or summary of
          the article represented as a fragment of HTML.</c>
                    
          <c><spanx style="verb">updated</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional time the article was last updated in the form of an 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/> "date-time".</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">url</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The permanent IRI of the article's HTML representation.</c>
          
          </texttable>

        </section>

        <section anchor="audio" title="Audio">
          <t>The "audio" object type represents audio content.</t>

          <t>At a minimum, an audio object has the following properties:</t>

          <texttable>
          <ttcol align="left" width="15%">Property</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left" width="21%">Value</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left">Description</ttcol>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">author</spanx></c>
          <c>Activity Object</c>
          <c>Activity Object, typically using the "person" object type, 
          responsible for the creation of the audio stream. If the audio 
          object appears within an activity, and the 
          <spanx style="verb">author</spanx> is the 
          <spanx style="verb">actor</spanx> for the activity, the 
          <spanx style="verb">author</spanx> property MAY be omitted</c>
                    
          <c><spanx style="verb">displayName</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The natural-language, human-readable and plain-text title for the 
          audio stream. HTML markup MUST NOT be included</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">embedCode</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>An optional HTML fragment that, when embedded in an HTML page, will
          provide an interactive player UI for the audio stream.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">id</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The unique identifier for the audio object.</c>
 
          <c><spanx style="verb">published</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional time the audio object was created in the form of an 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/> "date-time".</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">stream</spanx></c>
          <c>Media Link</c>
          <c>A link to the audio content itself. Represented in JSON as a 
          media link as defined in JSON Activity Streams 1.0.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">summary</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>Optional short, natural-language, human-readable snippet or summary of
          the audio stream represented as a fragment of HTML.</c>
                    
          <c><spanx style="verb">updated</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional time the audio object was last updated in the form of an 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/> "date-time".</c>
          
          </texttable>
        </section>

        <section anchor="badge" title="Badge">
          <t>The "badge" object type represents a Badge or Award granted to 
          an object (typically a person).</t>

          <t>At a minimum, an badge object has the following properties:</t>

          <texttable>
          <ttcol align="left" width="15%">Property</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left" width="21%">Value</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left">Description</ttcol>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">author</spanx></c>
          <c>Activity Object</c>
          <c>Activity Object, typically using the "person" object type, 
          responsible for the creation of the badge. If the badge 
          object appears within an activity, and the 
          <spanx style="verb">author</spanx> is the 
          <spanx style="verb">actor</spanx> for the activity, the 
          <spanx style="verb">author</spanx> property MAY be omitted</c>
                    
          <c><spanx style="verb">displayName</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The natural-language, human-readable and plain-text title for the 
          badge. HTML markup MUST NOT be included</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">id</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The unique identifier for the badge object.</c>
 
          <c><spanx style="verb">image</spanx></c>
          <c>Media Link</c>
          <c>An optional link to an image resource providing a visual representation
          of the badge. Processors MAY ignore images
          that are of an inappropriate size for their user interface.</c>
 
          <c><spanx style="verb">published</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional time the badge object was created in the form of an 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/> "date-time".</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">summary</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>Optional short, natural-language, human-readable description of
          the badge represented as a fragment of HTML.</c>
                    
          <c><spanx style="verb">updated</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional time the badge object was last updated in the form of an 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/> "date-time".</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">url</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The permanent IRI of the badge's HTML representation.</c>
          
          </texttable>
        </section>

        <section anchor="bookmark" title="Bookmark">
        
          <t>The "bookmark" object type represents a pointer to some URL --
          typically a web page. In most cases, a bookmark is specific to a
          given user and contains metadata chosen by that user. Bookmark
          Objects are similar in principle to the concept of bookmarks or
          favorites in a web browser. A bookmark represents a pointer to the
          URL, not the URL or the associated resource itself.</t>

          <t>When dealing with bookmarks it is important to note the
          distinction between the title, description, and URL of the bookmark
          itself and the title, content, and URL of the resource that is the
          target of the bookmark. In some implementations these MAY be the
          same, but bookmark managers often allow a user to edit the title and
          description of his or her own bookmarks to differ from the metadata
          on the target itself.</t>

          <t>Some implementations refer to this object type as a "link". This
          specification uses the term "bookmark" to avoid confusion with the
          general concept of hyperlinks which apply to all object types.</t>

          <t>Since bookmarks are often specific to a particular user, even
          though multiple users might have bookmarks pointing at the same
          resource, it is appropriate to use the <spanx style="verb">post</spanx> verb to describe the
          publication of such a bookmark. The <spanx style="verb">favorite</spanx> verb SHOULD
          be used when a user flags another user's bookmark as being a
          favorite without creating his own bookmark, or when a user flags his
          own bookmark as being a favorite as a special classification within
          his own bookmark collection.</t>

          <t>At a minimum, a bookmark object has the following properties:</t>

          <texttable>
          <ttcol align="left" width="15%">Property</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left" width="21%">Value</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left">Description</ttcol>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">author</spanx></c>
          <c>Activity Object</c>
          <c>Activity Object, typically using the "person" object type, 
          responsible for the creation of the bookmark. If the bookmark 
          object appears within an activity, and the 
          <spanx style="verb">author</spanx> is the 
          <spanx style="verb">actor</spanx> for the activity, the 
          <spanx style="verb">author</spanx> property MAY be omitted</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">displayName</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The natural-language, human-readable and plain-text title of the 
          bookmark as entered by the user who created it. HTML markup MUST NOT 
          be included. Publishers MAY user the title of the target resource
          as a default for this peroperty where a user has not entered a 
          customized value</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">id</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The unique identifier for the bookmark object.</c>
           
          <c><spanx style="verb">image</spanx></c>
          <c>Media Link</c>
          <c>An optional link to an image resource providing a visual representation
          of the bookmarked resource. Processors MAY ignore thumbnails
          that are of an inappropriate size for their user interface.</c>
                    
          <c><spanx style="verb">published</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional time the bookmark object was created in the form of an 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/> "date-time".</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">targetUrl</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The IRI of the item that is the target of the bookmark.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">updated</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional time the bookmark object was last updated in the form of an 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/> "date-time".</c>
          
          </texttable>

        </section>

        <section anchor="collection" title="Collection">
          <t>The "collection" object type represents a collection of objects 
          of any type. This object type can be used, for instance, to represent
          a collection of files like a folder, a collection of photos like 
          an album, and so forth.</t>

          <t>At a minimum, the collection object has the following properties:</t>

          <texttable>
          <ttcol align="left" width="15%">Property</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left" width="21%">Value</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left">Description</ttcol>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">author</spanx></c>
          <c>Activity Object</c>
          <c>Activity Object, typically using the "person" object type, 
          responsible for the creation of the collection. If the collection 
          object appears within an activity, and the 
          <spanx style="verb">author</spanx> is the 
          <spanx style="verb">actor</spanx> for the activity, the 
          <spanx style="verb">author</spanx> property MAY be omitted</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">displayName</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The natural-language, human-readable and plain-text title of the 
          collection.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">id</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The unique identifier for the collection object.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">image</spanx></c>
          <c>Media Link</c>
          <c>A link to an image resource that can be used as a preview image
          for the collection. Processors MAY ignore images that are of an 
          inappropriate size for their user interface.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">objectTypes</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> Array of Strings</c>
          <c>An optional array of JSON strings identifying the member 
          object types for the collection.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">published</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional time the collection object was created in the form of an 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/> "date-time".</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">updated</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional time the collection object was last updated in the form of an 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/> "date-time".</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">url</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The permanent IRI of the collection's HTML representation.</c>
          
          </texttable>

        </section>

        <section anchor="comment" title="Comment">
          <t>The "comment" object type represents a textual response to
          another object. The comment object type MUST NOT be used for other 
          kinds of responses, such as video replies or reviews.</t>

          <t>At a minimum, the comment object has the following properties:</t>

          <texttable>
          <ttcol align="left" width="15%">Property</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left" width="21%">Value</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left">Description</ttcol>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">author</spanx></c>
          <c>Activity Object</c>
          <c>Activity Object, typically using the "person" object type, 
          responsible for the creation of the comment. If the comment 
          object appears within an activity, and the 
          <spanx style="verb">author</spanx> is the 
          <spanx style="verb">actor</spanx> for the activity, the 
          <spanx style="verb">author</spanx> property MAY be omitted</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">content</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The main body content represented as a fragment of HTML. Publishers
          SHOULD include any markup necessary to achieve a similar presentation to
          that on the publisher's own HTML pages. Processors MAY remove all HTML
          markup and consider the comment to be plain text.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">displayName</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional, natural-language, human-readable and plain-text subject of the 
          comment. Many systems do not have the concept of a title or subject
          for a comment; such systems MUST omit the <spanx style="verb">displayName</spanx>
          property. Processors SHOULD refer to such comments as simply being 
          "a comment", with appropriate localization, if they are to be described
          in a sentence.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">id</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The unique identifier for the comment object.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">inReplyTo</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> Array of Objects</c>
          <c>A listing of one or more objects for which this object is a 
          response.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">published</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional time the comment object was created in the form of an 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/> "date-time".</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">updated</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional time the comment object was last updated in the form of an 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/> "date-time".</c>
          
          </texttable>
        </section>

        <section anchor="event" title="Event">
          <t>The "event" object type represents an event that occurs in a
          certain place during a particular interval of time.</t>

          <t>At a minimum, the event object has the following properties:</t>

          <texttable>
          <ttcol align="left" width="15%">Property</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left" width="21%">Value</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left">Description</ttcol>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">attending</spanx></c>
          <c>Collection object</c>
          <c>An optional link to a collection providing information about
          actors who have responded to the event object using the
          <spanx style="verb">rsvp-yes</spanx> verb.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">author</spanx></c>
          <c>Activity Object</c>
          <c>Activity Object, typically using the "person" object type, 
          responsible for the creation of the event. If the event 
          object appears within an activity, and the 
          <spanx style="verb">author</spanx> is the 
          <spanx style="verb">actor</spanx> for the activity, the 
          <spanx style="verb">author</spanx> property MAY be omitted</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">displayName</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The natural-language, human-readable and plain-text title of the 
          event.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">endTime</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The date and time that the event ends represented as a JSON
          String conforming to the "date-time" production in 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/></c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">id</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The unique identifier for the event object.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">location</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="location">Place</xref> object</c>
          <c>The optional, location or venue for the event expressed as a place 
          object as described in <xref target="location"/>.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">maybeAttending</spanx></c>
          <c>Collection object</c>
          <c>An optional link to a collection providing information about
          actors who have responded to the event object using the
          <spanx style="verb">rsvp-maybe</spanx> verb.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">notAttending</spanx></c>
          <c>Collection object</c>
          <c>An optional link to a collection providing information about
          actors who have responded to the event object using the
          <spanx style="verb">rsvp-no</spanx> verb.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">published</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional time the event object was created in the form of an 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/> "date-time".</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">startTime</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The date and time that the event begins represented as a JSON
          String conforming to the "date-time" production in 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/></c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">summary</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>Optional short, natural-language, human-readable description of
          the event represented as a fragment of HTML.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">updated</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional time the event object was last updated in the form of an 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/> "date-time".</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">url</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The permanent IRI of the event's HTML representation.</c>
 
          </texttable>
        </section>

        <section anchor="file" title="File">
          <t>The "file" object type represents some document or other file
          with no additional machine-readable semantics.</t>

          <t>It is intended that this type be used as a base type for other
          Objects that manifest as files, so that additional semantics can be
          added while providing a fallback ability for clients that do not
          support the more specific Object type.</t>

          <t>At a minimum, the file object has the following properties:</t>

          <texttable>
          <ttcol align="left" width="15%">Property</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left" width="21%">Value</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left">Description</ttcol>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">author</spanx></c>
          <c>Activity Object</c>
          <c>Activity Object, typically using the "person" object type, 
          responsible for the creation of the file. If the file 
          object appears within an activity, and the 
          <spanx style="verb">author</spanx> is the 
          <spanx style="verb">actor</spanx> for the activity, the 
          <spanx style="verb">author</spanx> property MAY be omitted</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">displayName</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The natural-language, human-readable and plain-text title of the 
          file.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">fileUrl</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The IRI of the file described by this object.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">id</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The unique identifier for the file object.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">published</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional time the file object was created in the form of an 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/> "date-time".</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">mimeType</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The MIME type of the file described by the object.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">updated</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional time the file object was last updated in the form of an 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/> "date-time".</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">url</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The permanent IRI of the file's HTML representation.</c>
          </texttable>
        </section>

        <section anchor="group" title="Group">
          <t>The "group" object type represents a grouping of objects in which
          member objects can join or leave.</t>

          <t>At a minimum, the group object has the following properties:</t>

          <texttable>
          <ttcol align="left" width="15%">Property</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left" width="21%">Value</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left">Description</ttcol>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">author</spanx></c>
          <c>Activity Object</c>
          <c>Activity Object, typically using the "person" object type, 
          responsible for the creation of the group. If the group 
          object appears within an activity, and the 
          <spanx style="verb">author</spanx> is the 
          <spanx style="verb">actor</spanx> for the activity, the 
          <spanx style="verb">author</spanx> property MAY be omitted</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">displayName</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The natural-language, human-readable and plain-text title of the 
          group.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">id</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The unique identifier for the group object.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">published</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional time the group object was created in the form of an 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/> "date-time".</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">updated</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional time the group object was last updated in the form of an 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/> "date-time".</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">url</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The permanent IRI of the group's HTML representation.</c>
          
          </texttable>
        </section>

        <section anchor="image" title="Image">
          <t>The "image" object type represents a graphical image.</t>

          <t>At a minimum, the image object has the following properties:</t>

          <texttable>
          <ttcol align="left" width="15%">Property</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left" width="21%">Value</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left">Description</ttcol>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">author</spanx></c>
          <c>Activity Object</c>
          <c>Activity Object, typically using the "person" object type, 
          responsible for the creation of the image. If the image 
          object appears within an activity, and the 
          <spanx style="verb">author</spanx> is the 
          <spanx style="verb">actor</spanx> for the activity, the 
          <spanx style="verb">author</spanx> property MAY be omitted</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">displayName</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>Optional natural-language and plain-text caption for the image. 
          HTML Markup MUST NOT be used.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">image</spanx></c>
          <c>Media Link</c>
          <c>A link to a thumbnail version of the image. Processors MAY ignore
          thumbnails that are of an inappropriate size for their user interface.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">fullImage</spanx></c>
          <c>Media Link</c>
          <c>A link to a larger -- ideally, full-size -- version of the image
          intended for standalone viewing.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">id</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The unique identifier for the image object.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">published</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional time the image object was created in the form of an 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/> "date-time".</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">summary</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>Optional, natural-language description of the image in the form
          of a fragment of HTML.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">updated</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional time the image object was last updated in the form of an 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/> "date-time".</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">url</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The permanent IRI of the image's HTML representation.</c>
          
          </texttable>
        </section>

        <section anchor="note" title="Note">
          <t>The "note" object type represents short-form text messages. This
          object type is intended for use in "micro-blogging" and in systems
          where users are invited to publish short, often plain-text messages
          whose useful lifespan is generally shorter than that of an article
          or weblog entry.</t>

          <t>A note is similar in structure to an article, but it does not
          have a title and its body tends to be shorter. Applications will
          often display the entire content of a note in an activity stream UI,
          whereas they MAY display only the title or the title and summary for
          a weblog entry.</t>

          <t>At a minimum, a note object has the following properties:</t>

          <texttable>
          <ttcol align="left" width="15%">Property</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left" width="21%">Value</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left">Description</ttcol>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">author</spanx></c>
          <c>Activity Object</c>
          <c>Activity Object, typically using the "person" object type, 
          responsible for the creation of the note. If the note 
          object appears within an activity, and the 
          <spanx style="verb">author</spanx> is the 
          <spanx style="verb">actor</spanx> for the activity, the 
          <spanx style="verb">author</spanx> property MAY be omitted</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">content</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The content of the note. Publishers SHOULD include any markup 
          necessary to achieve a similar presentation to that on the 
          publisher's own HTML pages, including any links that the service
          automatically adds. Processors MAY remove all HTML markup and 
          consider the comment to be plain text.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">id</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The unique identifier for the note object.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">published</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional time the note object was created in the form of an 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/> "date-time".</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">updated</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional time the note object was last updated in the form of an 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/> "date-time".</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">url</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The permanent IRI of the note's HTML representation.</c>
          
          </texttable>
        </section>

        <section anchor="person" title="Person">
          <t>The "person" object type represents a user account. This is often
          represents a person, but might also be a company or fictitious
          character that is being represented by a user account.</t>

          <t>At a minimum, the person object has the following properties:</t>

          <texttable>
          <ttcol align="left" width="15%">Property</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left" width="21%">Value</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left">Description</ttcol>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">displayName</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>A name that can be used for the person in the user interface. This
          is often a name by which the individual is known in a given context;
          no restriction is placed on what kind of name may be used here.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">image</spanx></c>
          <c>Media Link</c>
          <c>A link to an image representing the person. Processors MAY ignore
          thumbnails that are of an inappropriate size for their user interface.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">id</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The unique identifier for the person object.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">published</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional time the person object was created in the form of an 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/> "date-time".</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">updated</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional time the person object was last updated in the form of an 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/> "date-time".</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">url</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The permanent IRI of the person's HTML representation.</c>
          
          </texttable>
          
        </section>

        <section anchor="place" title="Place">
          <t>The "place" object type represents a location on Earth. Locations
          can be represented using geographic coordinates, a physical address,
          a free-form location name, or any combination of these.</t>

          <t>At a minimum, the place object has the following properties:</t>

          <texttable>
          <ttcol align="left" width="15%">Property</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left" width="21%">Value</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left">Description</ttcol>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">displayName</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>An optional natural-language, human-readable and plain-text name of the 
          place. HTML markup MUST NOT be included</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">id</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The unique identifier for the place object.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">position</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional latitude, longitude and altitude of the place as a point
          on Earth. Represented as an ISO 6709 compliant string. For instance
          <spanx style="verb">"position":"+27.5916+086.5640+8850/"</spanx>.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">address</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> Object</c>
          <c>A optional physical address represented as a JSON object with the properties
          defined in the table below.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">url</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The permanent IRI of the place's HTML representation.</c>
          
          </texttable>

          <t>The properties for the <spanx style="verb">address</spanx>
          property are:</t>

          <texttable>
          <ttcol align="left" width="15%">Property</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left" width="21%">Value</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left">Description</ttcol>

          <c><spanx style="verb">formatted</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The full mailing address formatted for display or use with 
          a mailing label.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">streetAddress</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The street address including house number, street name, P.O. Box, 
          and extended multi-line address information.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">locality</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The city or locality.</c>
     
          <c><spanx style="verb">region</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The state or region.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">postalCode</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The zip or postal code.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">country</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The country name component.</c>
          
          </texttable>
        </section>

        <section anchor="product" title="Product">
          <t>The "product" object type represents a commercial good or
          service.</t>

          <t>At a minimum, the product object has the following properties:</t>

          <texttable>
          <ttcol align="left" width="15%">Property</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left" width="21%">Value</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left">Description</ttcol>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">author</spanx></c>
          <c>Activity Object</c>
          <c>Activity Object, typically using the "person" object type, 
          responsible for the creation of the product. If the product
          object appears within an activity, and the 
          <spanx style="verb">author</spanx> is the 
          <spanx style="verb">actor</spanx> for the activity, the 
          <spanx style="verb">author</spanx> property MAY be omitted</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">displayName</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>Optional natural-language and plain-text name for the product. 
          HTML Markup MUST NOT be used.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">fullImage</spanx></c>
          <c>Media Link</c>
          <c>A link to a larger -- ideally, full-size -- version of the image 
          of the product.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">image</spanx></c>
          <c>Media Link</c>
          <c>A link to a thumbnail-sized image of the product. Processors MAY ignore
          thumbnails that are of an inappropriate size for their user interface.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">id</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The unique identifier for the product object.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">published</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional time the product object was created in the form of an 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/> "date-time".</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">summary</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>Optional, natural-language description of the product in the form
          of a fragment of HTML.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">updated</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional time the product object was last updated in the form of an 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/> "date-time".</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">url</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The permanent IRI of the product's HTML representation.</c>
          
          </texttable>
        </section>

        <section anchor="question" title="Question">
          <t>The "question" object type represents a question or poll.</t>
          
          <t>At a minimum, a question object has the following properties:</t>
          
          <texttable>
          <ttcol align="left" width="15%">Property</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left" width="21%">Value</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left">Description</ttcol>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">author</spanx></c>
          <c>Activity Object</c>
          <c>Activity Object, typically using the "person" object type, 
          responsible for the creation of the question. If the review
          object appears within an activity, and the 
          <spanx style="verb">author</spanx> is the 
          <spanx style="verb">actor</spanx> for the activity, the 
          <spanx style="verb">author</spanx> property MAY be omitted</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">content</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The content of the question in the form of a fragment of HTML. 
          Publishers SHOULD include any markup necessary to achieve a similar
          presentation to that on the publisher's own HTML pages, including
          any links that the service automatically adds. Processors MAY remove
          all HTML markup and consider the content to be plain text.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">displayName</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The title of the question. Some systems do not have the concept
          of a title for a question; such systems MUST omit the <spanx style="verb">displayName</spanx>
          property. Processors SHOULD refer to such questions as simply being "a question",
          with appropriate localization, if they are to be described in a sentence.</c>
                    
          <c><spanx style="verb">id</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The unique identifier for the question object.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">options</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> Array of Objects</c>
          <c>An optional listing of possible answers for the question. These
          may be of any <spanx style="verb">objectType</spanx> and SHOULD 
          contain an <spanx style="verb">id</spanx> property distinctly 
          identifying each possible answer.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">published</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional time the question object was created in the form of an 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/> "date-time".</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">updated</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional time the question object was last updated in the form of an 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/> "date-time".</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">url</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The permanent IRI of the question's HTML representation.</c>
          
          </texttable>
          
        </section>

        <section anchor="review" title="Review">
          <t>The "review" object type represents a primarily prose-based
          commentary on another object.</t>

          <t>At a minimum, a review object has the following properties:</t>

          <texttable>
          <ttcol align="left" width="15%">Property</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left" width="21%">Value</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left">Description</ttcol>

          <c><spanx style="verb">author</spanx></c>
          <c>Activity Object</c>
          <c>Activity Object, typically using the "person" object type, 
          responsible for the creation of the review. If the review
          object appears within an activity, and the 
          <spanx style="verb">author</spanx> is the 
          <spanx style="verb">actor</spanx> for the activity, the 
          <spanx style="verb">author</spanx> property MAY be omitted</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">content</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The content of the review in the form of a fragment of HTML. 
          Publishers SHOULD include any markup necessary to achieve a similar
          presentation to that on the publisher's own HTML pages, including
          any links that the service automatically adds. Processors MAY remove
          all HTML markup and consider the content to be plain text.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">displayName</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The title of the review. Many systems do not have the concept
          of a title for a review; such systems MUST omit the <spanx style="verb">displayName</spanx>
          property. Processors SHOULD refer to such reviews as simply being "a review",
          with appropriate localization, if they are to be described in a sentence.</c>
                    
          <c><spanx style="verb">id</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The unique identifier for the review object.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">published</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional time the review object was created in the form of an 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/> "date-time".</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">rating</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> Number</c>
          <c>A rating for the object given as a number between 1.0 and 
          5.0 inclusive with one decimal place of precision.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">updated</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional time the review object was last updated in the form of an 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/> "date-time".</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">url</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The permanent IRI of the review's HTML representation.</c>

          </texttable>
        </section>

        <section anchor="service" title="Service">
          <t>The "service" object type represents a website, personal website
          or blog, business, brand, or other entity that performs some kind of
          work for other entities, people, or services, or acts as kind of
          container for other objects.</t>

          <t>At a minimum, the service object has the following properties:</t>

          <texttable>
          <ttcol align="left" width="15%">Property</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left" width="21%">Value</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left">Description</ttcol>

          <c><spanx style="verb">displayName</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The natural-language, plain-text name of the service. HTML markup
          MUST NOT be used.</c>
                    
          <c><spanx style="verb">id</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The unique identifier for the service object.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">image</spanx></c>
          <c>Media Link</c>
          <c>A link to a small image representing the service.</c>          
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">published</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional time the service object was created in the form of an 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/> "date-time".</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">summary</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>A description of the service in the form of a fragment of HTML. 
          Publishers SHOULD include any markup necessary to achieve a similar
          presentation to that on the publisher's own HTML pages, including
          any links that the service automatically adds. Processors MAY remove
          all HTML markup and consider the content to be plain text.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">updated</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional time the service object was last updated in the form of an 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/> "date-time".</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">url</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The permanent IRI of the service's HTML representation.</c>

          </texttable>

        </section>

        <section anchor="video" title="Video">
          <t>The "video" object type represents video content, which usually
          consists of a motion picture track and an audio track.</t>

          <t>At a minimum, the video object has the following properties:</t>

          <texttable>
          <ttcol align="left" width="15%">Property</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left" width="21%">Value</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left">Description</ttcol>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">author</spanx></c>
          <c>Activity Object</c>
          <c>Activity Object, typically using the "person" object type, 
          responsible for the creation of the video stream. If the video 
          object appears within an activity, and the 
          <spanx style="verb">author</spanx> is the 
          <spanx style="verb">actor</spanx> for the activity, the 
          <spanx style="verb">author</spanx> property MAY be omitted</c>
                    
          <c><spanx style="verb">displayName</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The natural-language, human-readable and plain-text title for the 
          video stream. HTML markup MUST NOT be included</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">embedCode</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>An optional HTML fragment that, when embedded in an HTML page, will
          provide an interactive player UI for the video stream.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">id</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The unique identifier for the video object.</c>
 
          <c><spanx style="verb">published</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional time the video object was created in the form of an 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/> "date-time".</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">stream</spanx></c>
          <c>Media Link</c>
          <c>A link to the video content itself. Represented in JSON as a 
          media link as defined in JSON Activity Streams 1.0.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">summary</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>Optional short, natural-language, human-readable snippet or summary of
          the video stream represented as a fragment of HTML.</c>
                    
          <c><spanx style="verb">updated</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The optional time the video object was last updated in the form of an 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/> "date-time".</c>
          
          </texttable>
        </section>
      </section>

      <section title="Base Extension Properties">
        <t>This specification defines an initial set of extension properties
        that can be used with all activities or objects.</t>

        <section anchor="location" title="Location">
          <t>Location data can be added to any object type or activity. Location 
          can be specified via geographic coordinates, a street address, 
          a free-form location name or any combination of these.</t>
          
          <t>Within a JSON-serialized Activity Stream, the Location is represented
          using a property named <spanx style="verb">location</spanx> whose 
          value is a <xref target="place">Place</xref> object. The objectType
          property of this object MAY be omitted.</t>
          
          <t>When appearing within an activity, the location data indicates
          the location where the activity occurred. When appearing within an
          object, the location data indicates the location of that
          object at the time the activity occurred.</t>
          
          <t>For example:</t>
<figure><artwork><![CDATA[
  {
    "objectType": "person",
    "displayName": "John Doe",
    "location": {
      "displayName": "Mount Everest",
      "position": "+27.5916+086.5640+8850/"
    }
  }
]]></artwork></figure>
          
        </section>

        <section anchor="mood-property" title="Mood">
          <t>Mood describes the mood of the user when the activity was
          performed. This is usually collected via an extra field in the user
          interface used to perform the activity. For the purpose of this
          schema, a mood is a freeform, short mood keyword or phrase along
          with an optional mood icon image.</t>

          <t>In JSON, Moods are included within an object or activity using
          a property named <spanx style="verb">mood</spanx> whose value 
          is a JSON object with the following properties:</t>

          <texttable>
          <ttcol align="left" width="15%">Property</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left" width="21%">Value</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left">Description</ttcol>

          <c><spanx style="verb">displayName</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The natural-language, human-readable and plain-text keyword or 
          phrase describing the mood. HTML markup MUST NOT be included</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">image</spanx></c>
          <c>Media Link</c>
          <c>An optional image that provides a visual representation of the mood.</c>
          
          </texttable>     
          
          <t>For example:</t>
<figure><artwork><![CDATA[
  {
    "objectType": "note",
    "content": "Working on the activity streams spec",
    "mood": {
      "displayName": "Optimistic",
      "image": "http://example.org/moods/optimistic.png"
    }
  }
]]></artwork></figure>
          
        </section>
        
        <section anchor="rating-property" title="Rating">
          <t>A rating given as a number between 1.0 and 5.0 inclusive with 
          one decimal place of precision. Represented in JSON as a property 
          called <spanx style="verb">rating</spanx> whose value is a JSON 
          number giving the rating.</t>
          
          <t>Ratings are generally most useful only for particular types 
          of objects, such as audio, video, photos and places.</t>
          
          <t>For example:</t>
<figure><artwork><![CDATA[
  {
    "objectType": "review",
    "content": "This is a great product",
    "rating": 3.5
  }
]]></artwork></figure>
          
        </section>
        
        <section anchor="source" title="Source">
    
          <t>The <spanx style="verb">source</spanx> property provides a reference
          to the original source of an object or activity. The value of the 
          <spanx style="verb">source</spanx> property is an Object of any 
          object type.</t>
          
          <t>The <spanx style="verb">source</spanx> property is closely related to the 
          <spanx style="verb">generator</spanx> and <spanx style="verb">provider</spanx>
          properties but serves the distinct purpose of identifying where the 
          activity or object was originally published as opposed to identifying 
          the applications that generated or published it.</t>
          
          <t>For example:</t>
<figure><artwork><![CDATA[
  {
    "actor": {
      "objectType": "person",
      "displayName": "Joe"
    },
    "verb": "post",
    "object": {
      "objectType": "photo",
      "image": "http://example.org/photos/fluffycat.jpg"
    },
    "source": {
      "objectType": "collection",
      "displayName": "Joe's Photo's",
      "url": "http://example.org/joes/photos"
    }
  }
]]></artwork></figure>
    
        </section>
        
        <section anchor="tags-property" title="Tags">
          <t>A listing of the objects that have been associated with a 
          particular object using the <spanx style="verb">tag</spanx> verb. 
          Represented in JSON using a property named <spanx style="verb">tags</spanx>
          whose value is  an Array of objects.</t>
        </section>
        
        <t>For example:</t>
<figure><artwork><![CDATA[
  {
    "objectType": "photo",
    "image": "http://example.org/photos/fluffycat.jpg",
    "tags": [
      {
        "objectType": "person",
        "displayName": "John"
      },
      {
        "objectType": "person",
        "displayName": "Jane"
      }
    ]
  }
]]></artwork></figure>
        
      </section>
    
  </middle>

  <back>
    <references title="Normative References">

      <reference anchor="RFC2119">
        <front>
          <title>RFC 2119</title>

          <author>
            <organization></organization>
          </author>

          <date />
        </front>
      </reference>

      <reference anchor="RFC3987">
        <front>
          <title>Internationalized Resource Identifiers (IRIs)</title>

          <author>
            <organization></organization>
          </author>

          <date />
        </front>
      </reference>

<reference anchor="RFC4627">
        <front>
          <title>The application/json Media Type for JavaScript Object
          Notation (JSON)</title>

          <author fullname="Douglas Crockford" initials="D."
                  surname="Crockford">
            <organization>JSON.org</organization>
          </author>

          <date month="July" year="2006" />
        </front>
      </reference>

      <reference anchor="RFC3339">
        <front>
          <title>Date and Time on the Internet: Timestamps</title>

          <author fullname="Graham Klyne" initials="G." surname="Klyne">
            <organization></organization>
          </author>

          <date month="July" year="2002" />
        </front>
      </reference>

      <reference anchor="activitystreams">
        <front>
          <title>JSON Activity Streams 1.0</title>

    <author fullname="James M Snell" initials="J.M." surname="Snell">
      <organization>IBM</organization>
    </author>

    <author fullname="Martin Atkins" initials="M." surname="Atkins">
      <organization>SAY Media</organization>
    </author>

    <author fullname="Will Norris" initials="W." surname="Norris">
      <organization>Google</organization>
    </author>

    <author fullname="Chris Messina" initials="C." surname="Messina">
      <organization>Citizen Agency, Google</organization>
    </author>

    <author fullname="Monica Wilkinson" initials="M." surname="Wilkinson">
      <organization>MySpace, Facebook, Socialcast</organization>
    </author>

    <author fullname="Rob Dolin" initials="R." surname="Dolin">
      <organization>Microsoft</organization>
    </author>

          <date month="May" year="2011" />
        </front>
      </reference>
    </references>

    <section title="Acknowledgements">
      <t>...</t>
    </section>
  </back>
</rfc>
