<?xml version="1.0" encoding="US-ASCII"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='./rfc2629.xslt' ?>
<!DOCTYPE rfc SYSTEM "rfc2629.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY rfc2119 PUBLIC '' 'http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.2119.xml'> 
  <!ENTITY rfc1951 PUBLIC '' 'http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.1951.xml'>
  <!ENTITY rfc1952 PUBLIC '' 'http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.1952.xml'>
  <!ENTITY rfc3339 PUBLIC '' 'http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.3339.xml'>
  <!ENTITY rfc4627 PUBLIC '' 'http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.4627.xml'>
  <!ENTITY rfc4646 PUBLIC '' 'http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.4646.xml'>
  <!ENTITY rfc3986 PUBLIC '' 'http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.3986.xml'>
  <!ENTITY rfc3987 PUBLIC '' 'http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.3987.xml'>
  <!ENTITY rfc5988 PUBLIC '' 'http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.5988.xml'>
]>
<?rfc toc="yes"?>
<?rfc tocompact="yes"?>
<?rfc tocdepth="3"?>
<?rfc tocindent="yes"?>
<?rfc symrefs="yes"?>
<?rfc sortrefs="yes"?>
<?rfc comments="yes"?>
<?rfc inline="yes"?>
<?rfc compact="yes"?>
<?rfc subcompact="no"?>
<?rfc private="Activity Streams Working Group"?>
<rfc>
  <front>
    <title abbrev="ActivitySchema">Activity Base Schema (Draft)</title>

    <author fullname="James M Snell" initials="J.M." surname="Snell">
      <organization>IBM</organization>
    </author>

    <author fullname="Martin Atkins" initials="M." surname="Atkins">
      <organization>SAY Media</organization>
    </author>

    <author fullname="David Recordon" initials="D." surname="Recordon">
      <organization>Six Apart, Facebook</organization>
    </author>

    <author fullname="Chris Messina" initials="C." surname="Messina">
      <organization>Citizen Agency, Google</organization>
    </author>

    <author fullname="Monica Keller" initials="M." surname="Keller">
      <organization>MySpace, Facebook</organization>
    </author>

    <author fullname="Ari Steinberg" initials="A." surname="Steinberg">
      <organization>Facebook</organization>
    </author>

    <author fullname="Rob Dolin" initials="R." surname="Dolin">
      <organization>Microsoft</organization>
    </author>

    <date month="August" year="2012" /> 

    <abstract>
      <t>This document presents a base set of Object types and Verbs for use
      with Activity Streams.</t>
    </abstract>

    <note title="Requirements Language">
      <t>The key words "MUST", "MUST NOT", "REQUIRED", "SHALL", "SHALL NOT",
      "SHOULD", "SHOULD NOT", "RECOMMENDED", "MAY", and "OPTIONAL" in this
      document are to be interpreted as described in <xref
      target="RFC2119">RFC 2119</xref>.</t>
    </note>
  </front>

  <middle>
    <section title="Introduction">
      <t>This document presents a base set of object types and verbs for use
      with Activity Streams.</t>   
            
      <section title="Notational Conventions">
        <t>This specification allows the use of <xref target="RFC3987">IRIs</xref>. 
        Every <xref target="RFC3986">URI</xref> is also an IRI, so a URI MAY be 
        used wherever an IRI is named. When an IRI that is not also a URI is 
        given for dereferencing, it MUST be mapped to a URI using the steps in 
        Section 3.1 of <xref target="RFC3987"/>. When an IRI is serving as an 
        identifier, it MUST NOT be so mapped.</t>
        
        <t>Unless otherwise specified, all properties specifying date and
        time values MUST conform to the "date-time" production in <xref target="RFC3339" />.
        In addition, an uppercase "T" character MUST be used to separate date
        and time, and an uppercase "Z" character MUST be present in the absence of
        a numeric time zone offset.</t>
        
      </section>  
    </section>

      <section anchor="verbs" title="Verbs">
      
        <t>This specification defines the following core verbs in addition
        to the default <spanx style="verb">post</spanx> verb that is defined in Section 6 of 
        <xref target="activitystreams"/>:</t>
      
        <texttable>
          <ttcol align="left" width="15%">Verb</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left">Description</ttcol>
      
          <c><spanx style="verb">accept</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that that the actor has accepted the object. For 
          instance, a person accepting an award, or accepting an assignment.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">access</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has accessed the object. For instance,
          a person accessing a room, or accessing a file.</c>
      
          <c><spanx style="verb">acknowledge</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has acknowledged the object. This 
          effectively signals that the actor is aware of the object's
          existence.</c>
      
          <c><spanx style="verb">add</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has added the object to the target. 
          For instance, adding a photo to an album.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">agree</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor agrees with the object. For example, 
          a person agreeing with an argument, or expressing agreement with
          a particular issue.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">append</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has appended the object to the target.
          For instance, a person appending a new record to a database.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">approve</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has approved the object. For instance,
          a manager might approve a travel request.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">archive</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has archived the object.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">assign</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has assigned the object to the target.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">at</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor is currently located at the object. For 
          instance, a person being at a specific physical location.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">attach</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has attached the object to the target.
          For instance, a person attaching a file to a wiki page or an email.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">attend</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has attended the object. For instance,
          a person attending a meeting.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">author</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has authored the object. Note that this
          is a more specific form of the verb "create".</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">authorize</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has authorized the object. If a target
          is specified, it means that the authorization is specifically in 
          regards to the target. For instance, a service can authorize a 
          person to access a given application; in which case the actor is the
          service, the object is the person, and the target is the application.
          In contrast, a person can authorize a request; in which case the 
          actor is the person and the object is the request and there might be 
          no explicit target.</c>
                    
          <c><spanx style="verb">borrow</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has borrowed the object. If a target
          is specified, it identifies the entity from which the object was 
          borrowed. For instance, if a person borrows a book from a library,
          the person is the actor, the book is the object and the library 
          is the target.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">build</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has built the object. For example, 
          if a person builds a model or compiles code.</c>
                    
          <c><spanx style="verb">cancel</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has canceled the object. For 
          instance, canceling a calendar event.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">close</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has closed the object. For instance,
          the object could represent a ticket being tracked in an issue
          management system.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">complete</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has completed the object.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">confirm</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has confirmed or agrees with the object.
          For instance, a software developer might confirm an issue reported
          against a product.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">consume</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has consumed the object. The 
          specific meaning is dependent largely on the object's type.
          For instance, an actor may "consume" an audio object, indicating
          that the actor has listened to it; or an actor may "consume"
          a book, indicating that the book has been read. As such, the 
          "consume" verb is a more generic form of other more specific 
          verbs such as "read" and "play".</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">checkin</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has checked-in to the object. For 
          instance, a person checking-in to a Place.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">create</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has created the object.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">delete</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has deleted the object. This 
          implies, but does not require, the permanent destruction of the 
          object.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">deliver</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has delivered the object. For example,
          delivering a package.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">deny</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has denied the object. For example,
          a manager may deny a travel request.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">disagree</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor disagrees with the object.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">dislike</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor dislikes the object. Note that the 
          "dislike" verb is distinct from the "unlike" verb which assumes
          that the object had been previously "liked".</c>
      
          <c><spanx style="verb">experience</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has experienced the object in some 
          manner. Note that, depending on the specific object types used 
          for both the actor and object, the meaning of this verb can 
          overlap that of the "consume" and "play" verbs. For instance, 
          a person might "experience" a movie; or "play" the movie; or "consume"
          the movie. The "experience" verb can be considered a more generic
          form of other more specific verbs as "consume", "play", "watch", 
          "listen", and "read"</c>
      
          <c><spanx style="verb">favorite</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor marked the object as an item of 
          special interest.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">find</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has found the object.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">flag-as-inappropriate</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has flagged the object as being 
          inappropriate for some reason. When using this verb, the 
          <spanx style="verb">context</spanx> property, as specified 
          within <xref target="context"/> can be used to 
          provide additional detail about why the object has been 
          flagged.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">follow</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor began following the activity of the 
          object. In most cases, the objectType will be a "person", but it can 
          potentially be of any type that can sensibly generate activity.
          Processors MAY ignore (silently drop) successive identical "follow" 
          activities.</c>
                
          <c><spanx style="verb">give</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor is giving an object to the target.
          Examples include one person giving a <spanx style="verb">badge</spanx>
          object to another person. The <spanx style="verb">object</spanx>
          identifies the object being given. The <spanx style="verb">target</spanx>
          identifies the receiver.</c>
        
          <c><spanx style="verb">host</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor is hosting the object. As in hosting 
          an event, or hosting a service.</c>
        
          <c><spanx style="verb">ignore</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has ignored the object. For instance, 
          this verb may be used when an actor has ignored a friend request, 
          in which case the object may be the <spanx style="verb">request-friend</spanx>
          activity.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">insert</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has inserted the object into the target.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">install</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has installed the object, as in 
          installing an application.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">interact</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has interacted with the object. For instance,
          when one person interacts with another.</c>
        
          <c><spanx style="verb">invite</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has invited the object, typically a 
          person object, to join or participate in the object described by
          the <spanx style="verb">target</spanx>. The target could, for instance,
          be an event, group or a service.</c>
        
          <c><spanx style="verb">join</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has become a member of the object. This 
          specification only defines the meaning of this verb when the 
          <spanx style="verb">object</spanx> of the Activity has an
          <spanx style="verb">objectType</spanx> of <spanx style="verb">group</spanx>, 
          though implementors need to be prepared to handle other types of objects.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">leave</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has left the object. For instance, 
          a Person leaving a Group or checking-out of a Place.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">like</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor marked the object as an item of special 
          interest. The "like" verb is considered to be an alias of "favorite". 
          The two verb are semantically identical.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">listen</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has listened to the object. This is typically
          only applicable for objects representing audio content, such as music,
          and audio-book, or a radio broadcast. The "listen" verb is a more specific
          form of the "consume", "experience" and "play" verbs.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">lose</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has lost the object. For instance, if a 
          person loses a game.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">make-friend</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates the creation of a friendship that is reciprocated by 
          the object. Since this verb implies an activity on the part of its object,
          processors MUST NOT accept activities with this verb unless they are
          able to verify through some external means that there is in fact a
          reciprocated connection. For example, a processor may have received
          a guarantee from a particular publisher that the publisher will only
          use this Verb in cases where a reciprocal relationship exists.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">open</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has opened the object. For instance,
          the object could represent a ticket being tracked in an issue
          management system.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">play</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor spent some time enjoying the object. 
          For example, if the object is a video this indicates that the subject 
          watched all or part of the video. The "play" verb is a more specific 
          form of the "consume" verb.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">present</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has presented the object. For instance,
          when a person gives a presentation at a conference.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">purchase</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has purchased the object. If a target is
          specified, in indicates the entity from which the object was purchased.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">qualify</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has qualified for the object. If a target
          is specified, it indicates the context within which the qualification
          applies.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">read</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor read the object. This is typically only
          applicable for objects representing printed or written content, such 
          as a book, a message or a comment. The "read" verb is a more specific
          form of the "consume", "experience" and "play" verbs.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">receive</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor is receiving an object.
          Examples include a person receiving a <spanx style="verb">badge</spanx>
          object. The <spanx style="verb">object</spanx>
          identifies the object being received.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">reject</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has rejected the object.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">remove</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has removed the object from the target.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">remove-friend</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has removed the object from the collection
          of friends.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">replace</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has replaced the target with the object.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">request</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has requested the object. If a target is
          specified, it indicates the entity from which the object is being 
          requested.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">request-friend</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates the creation of a friendship that has not yet been reciprocated by 
          the object.</c>
                    
          <c><spanx style="verb">resolve</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has resolved the object. For instance,
          the object could represent a ticket being tracked in an issue
          management system.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">return</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has returned the object. If a target is
          specified, it indicates the entity to which the object was returned.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">retract</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has retracted the object. For instance,
          if an actor wishes to retract a previously published activity, 
          the object would be the previously published activity that is being
          retracted.</c>
        
          <c><spanx style="verb">rsvp-maybe</spanx></c> 
          <c>The "possible RSVP" verb indicates that the actor has made a
          possible RSVP for the object. This specification only defines the
          meaning of this verb when its object is an event (see <xref
          target="event"></xref>), though implementors need to be prepared to
          handle other object types. The use of this verb is only appropriate 
          when the RSVP was created by an explicit action by the actor. It 
          is not appropriate to use this verb when a user has been added as 
          an attendee by an event organiser or administrator.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">rsvp-no</spanx></c>
          <c>The "negative RSVP" verb indicates that the actor has made a
          negative RSVP for the object. This specification only defines the
          meaning of this verb when its object is an event (see <xref
          target="event"></xref>), though implementors need to be prepared to
          handle other object types. The use of this verb is only appropriate 
          when the RSVP was created by an explicit action by the actor. It is 
          not appropriate to use this verb when a user has been added as an 
          attendee by an event organiser or administrator.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">rsvp-yes</spanx></c>
          <c>The "positive RSVP" verb indicates that the actor has made a
          positive RSVP for an object. This specification only defines the
          meaning of this verb when its object is an event (see <xref
          target="event" />), though implementors need to be prepared to
          handle other object types. The use of this verb is only appropriate 
          when the RSVP was created by an explicit action by the actor. It 
          is not appropriate to use this verb when a user has been added as 
          an attendee by an event organiser or administrator.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">satisfy</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has satisfied the object. If a target 
          is specified, it indicate the context within which the object was 
          satisfied. For instance, if a person satisfies the requirements for
          a particular challenge, the person is the actor; the requirement is
          the object; and the challenge is the target.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">save</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has called out the object as being of 
          interest primarily to him- or herself. Though this action MAY be 
          shared publicly, the implication is that the object has been saved 
          primarily for the actor's own benefit rather than to show it to 
          others as would be indicated by the "share" verb.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">schedule</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has scheduled the object. For instance,
          scheduling a meeting.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">search</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor is or has searched for the object. If
          a target is specified, it indicates the context within which the 
          search is or has been conducted.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">sell</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has sold the object. If a target is 
          specified, it indicates the entity to which the object was sold.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">send</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has sent the object. If a target is 
          specified, it indicates the entity to which the object was sent.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">share</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has called out the object to readers. 
          In most cases, the actor did not create the object being shared, 
          but is instead drawing attention to it.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">sponsor</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has sponsored the object. If a target
          is specified, it indicates the context within which the sponsorship
          is offered. For instance, a company can sponsor an event; or an 
          individual can sponsor a project; etc.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">start</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has started the object. For instance, 
          when a person starts a project.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">stop-following</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has stopped following the object.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">submit</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has submitted the object. If a target
          is specified, it indicates the entity to which the object was submitted.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">tag</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has associated the object with the target.
          For example, if the actor specifies that a particular user 
          appears in a photo. the object is the user and the target is the photo.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">terminate</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has terminated the object. </c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">tie</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has neither won or lost the object. This
          verb is generally only applicable when the object represents some form
          of competition, such as a game.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">unfavorite</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has removed the object from the collection
          of favorited items.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">unlike</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has removed the object from the collection
          of liked items.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">unsatisfy</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has not satisfied the object. If a target
          is specified, it indicates the context within which the object was not
          satisfied. For instance, if a person fails to satisfy the requirements 
          of some particular challenge, the person is the actor; the requirement 
          is the object and the challenge is the target.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">unsave</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has removed the object from the collection
          of saved items.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">unshare</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor is no longer sharing the object. If a 
          target is specified, it indicates the entity with whom the object is
          no longer being shared.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">update</spanx></c>
          <c>The "update" verb indicates that the actor has modified the
          object. Use of the "update" verb is generally reserved to indicate 
          modifications to existing objects or data such as changing an existing
          user's profile information.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">use</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has used the object in some manner.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">watch</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has watched the object. This verb is 
          typically applicable only when the object represents dynamic, visible
          content such as a movie, a television show or a public performance.
          This verb is a more specific form of the verbs "experience", "play"
          and "consume".</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">win</spanx></c>
          <c>Indicates that the actor has won the object. This verb is typically
          applicable only when the object represents some form of competition, 
          such as a game.</c>
          
        </texttable>

      </section>

      <section anchor="object-types" title="Object Types">

        <t>The table contains the core set of common objectTypes in addition
        to the <spanx style="verb">activity</spanx> objectType defined in 
        Section 7 of <xref target="activitystreams"/>.</t>
      
        <t>All Activity Stream Objects inherit the same fundamental set of 
        basic properties as defined in section 3.4 of <xref target="activitystreams"/>.
        In addition to these, objects of any specific type are permitted to 
        introduce additional optional or required properties that are meaningful
        to objects of that type.</t>

        <texttable>
          <ttcol align="left" width="15%">Object Type</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left">Description</ttcol>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">alert</spanx></c>
          <c>Represents any kind of significant notification.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">application</spanx></c>
          <c>Represents any kind of software application.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">article</spanx></c>
          <c>Represents objects such as news articles, knowledge base entries, 
          or other similar construct. Such objects generally consist of paragraphs 
          of text, in some cases incorporating embedded media such as photos 
          and inline hyperlinks to other resources.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">audio</spanx></c>
          <c>Represents audio content of any kind. Objects of this type MAY
          contain an additional property as specified in <xref target="audio-video"/>.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">badge</spanx></c>
          <c>Represents a badge or award granted to an object (typically a 
          <spanx style="verb">person</spanx> object)</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">binary</spanx></c>
          <c>Objects of this type are used to carry arbirary Base64-encoded
          binary data within an Activity Stream object. It is primarily 
          intended to attach binary data to other types of objects through
          the use of the <spanx style="verb">attachments</spanx> property. 
          Objects of this type will contain the additional properties specified in 
          <xref target="binary"/>.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">bookmark</spanx></c>
          <c>Represents a pointer to some URL -- typically a web page. In most 
          cases, bookmarks are specific to a given user and contain metadata 
          chosen by that user. Bookmark Objects are similar in principle to the 
          concept of bookmarks or favorites in a web browser. A bookmark 
          represents a pointer to the URL, not the URL or the associated resource 
          itself. Objects of this type SHOULD contain an additional 
          <spanx style="verb">targetUrl</spanx> property whose value is a 
          String containing the IRI of the target of the bookmark.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">collection</spanx></c>
          <c>Represents a generic collection of objects of any type. This object
          type can be used, for instance, to represent a collection of files 
          like a folder; a collection of photos like an album; and so forth. 
          Objects of this type MAY contain an additional <spanx style="verb">objectTypes</spanx>
          property whose value is an Array of Strings specifying the expected
          objectType of objects contained within the collection.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">comment</spanx></c>
          <c>Represents a textual response to another object. Objects of this 
          type MAY contain an additional <spanx style="verb">inReplyTo</spanx>
          property whose value is an Array of one or more other Activity Stream 
          Objects for which the object is to be considered a response.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">device</spanx></c>
          <c>Represents a device of any sort.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">event</spanx></c>
          <c>Represents an event that occurs at a certain location during 
          a particular period of time. Objects of this type MAY contain the 
          additional properties specified in <xref target="event"/>.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">file</spanx></c>
          <c>Represents any form of document or file. Objects of this type 
          MAY contain an additional <spanx style="verb">fileUrl</spanx>
          property whose value a dereferenceable IRI that can be used to 
          retrieve the file; and an additional <spanx style="verb">mimeType</spanx>
          property whose value is the MIME type of the file described by the 
          object.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">game</spanx></c>
          <c>Represents a game or competition of any kind.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">group</spanx></c>
          <c>Represents a grouping of objects in which member objects can 
          join or leave.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">image</spanx></c>
          <c>Represents a graphical image. Objects of this type MAY contain
          an additional <spanx style="verb">fullImage</spanx> property whose 
          value is an Activity Streams Media Link to a "full-sized" representation
          of the image.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">issue</spanx></c>
          <c>Represents a report about a problem or situation that needs to 
          be resolved. For instance, the <spanx style="verb">issue</spanx> object
          can be used to represent reports detailing software defects, or 
          reports of acceptable use violations, and so forth. Objects of this 
          type MAY contain the additional properties specified in <xref target="issue"/>.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">job</spanx></c>
          <c>Represents information about a job or a job posting.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">note</spanx></c>
          <c>Represents a short-form text message. This object is intended 
          primarily for use in "micro-blogging" scenarios and in systems
          where users are invited to publish short, often plain-text messages
          whose useful lifespan is generally shorter than that of an article
          of weblog entry. A note is similar in structure to an article, but 
          typically does not have a title or distinct paragraphs and tends to 
          be much shorter in length.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">offer</spanx></c>
          <c>Represents an offer of any kind.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">organization</spanx></c>
          <c>Represents an organization of any kind.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">page</spanx></c>
          <c>Represents an area, typically a web page, that is representative 
          of, and generally managed by a particular entity. Such areas are 
          usually dedicated to displaying descriptive information about the 
          entity and showcasing recent content such as articles, photographs and 
          videos. Most social networking applications, for example, provide 
          individual users with their own dedicated "profile" pages. Several
          allow similar types of pages to be created for commercial entities,
          organizations or events. While the specific details of how pages 
          are implemented, their characteristics and use may vary, the one 
          unifying property is that they are typically "owned" by a single 
          entity that is represented by the content provided by the page itself.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">person</spanx></c>
          <c>Represents an individual person.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">place</spanx></c>
          <c>Represents a physical location. Locations can be represented 
          using geographic coordinates, a physical address, a free-form 
          location name, or any combination of these. Objects of this type
          MAY contain the additional properties specified in 
          <xref target="place"/>.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">process</spanx></c>
          <c>Represents any form of process. For instance, a long-running 
          task that is started and expected to continue operating for a 
          period of time.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">product</spanx></c>
          <c>Represents a commercial good or service. Objects of this type
          MAY contain an additional <spanx style="verb">fullImage</spanx> 
          property whose value is an Activity Streams Media Link to an image
          resource representative of the product.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">question</spanx></c>
          <c>Represents a question or a poll. Objects of this type MAY contain
          an additional <spanx style="verb">options</spanx> property whose value
          is an Array of possible answers to the question in the form of 
          Activity Stream objects of any type.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">review</spanx></c>
          <c>Represents a primarily prose-based commentary on another object.
          Objects of this type MAY contain a <spanx style="verb">rating</spanx>
          property as specified in <xref target="rating-property"/>.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">service</spanx></c>
          <c>Represents any form of hosted or consumable service that performs
          some kind of work or benefit for other entities. Examples of such 
          objects include websites, businesses, etc.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">task</spanx></c>
          <c>Represents an activity that has yet to be completed. Objects of
          this type can contain additional properties as specified in 
          <xref target="task"/>.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">video</spanx></c>
          <c>Represents video content of any kind. Objects of this type MAY
          contain additional properties as specified in <xref target="audio-video"/>.</c>
          
        </texttable>
      
        <section anchor="audio-video" title="Audio and Video Objects">
        
        <t>In addition to the core properties shared by all Activity Streams
        Objects, "audio" and "video" objects MAY contain the following 
        properties:</t>
        
        <texttable>
        <ttcol align="left" width="15%">Property</ttcol>
        <ttcol align="left" width="21%">Value</ttcol>
        <ttcol align="left">Description</ttcol>
        
        <c><spanx style="verb">embedCode</spanx></c>
        <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
        <c>A fragment of HTML markup that, when embedded within another HTML
        page, provides an interactive user-interface for viewing or listening
        to the video or audio stream.</c>
        
        <c><spanx style="verb">stream</spanx></c>
        <c>Media Link</c>
        <c>An Activity Streams Media Link to the video or audio content itself.</c>
        
        </texttable>
        
        </section>
      
        <section anchor="binary" title="Binary Objects">
        
          <t>The "binary" object type is used to carry arbitrary Base64-encoded
          binary data within an Activity Stream object. It is primarily
          intended to attach binary data to other object types through the
          use of the "attachments" property.</t>
          
          <t>In addition to the core properties shared by all Activity Streams
          Objects, "binary" objects MAY contain the following properties:</t>

          <texttable>
          <ttcol align="left" width="15%">Property</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left" width="21%">Value</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left">Description</ttcol>
                    
          <c><spanx style="verb">compression</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>An optional token identifying a compression algorithm applied to the
          binary data prior to Base64-encoding. Possible algorithms are 
          "deflate" and "gzip", respectively indicating the use of the 
          compression mechanisms defined by <xref target="RFC1951" /> and
          <xref target="RFC1952"/>. Additional compression algorithms MAY
          be used but are not defined by this specification. Note that 
          previous versions of this specification allowed for multiple
          compression algorithms to be applied and listed using a comma-separated
          format. The use of multiple compressions is no longer permitted.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">data</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The URL-Safe Base64-encoded representation of the binary data.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">fileUrl</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>An optional IRI for the binary data described by this object.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">length</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> Number</c>
          <c>The total number of unencoded, uncompressed octets contained 
          within the "data" field represented as a non-negative integer value.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">md5</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>An optional MD5 checksum calculated over the unencoded, uncompressed
          octets contained with the "data" field.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">mimeType</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The MIME type of the object described by the object.</c>
          
          </texttable>
          
          <t>Note that the <spanx style="verb">binary</spanx> and 
          <spanx style="verb">file</spanx> objectTypes are conceptually
          related. The key difference between the two lies in the fact
          that the <spanx style="verb">file</spanx> objectType is more
          representative of the abstract description of a file or document
          while the <spanx style="verb">binary</spanx> objectType represents
          the actual, concrete stream of octets that make up the content.</t>
          
          <t>Because of their close relationship, it is possible for the 
          <spanx style="verb">file</spanx> objectType to share the same 
          basic properties as the <spanx style="verb">binary</spanx> 
          objectType. That is, a <spanx style="verb">file</spanx> MAY
          also have properties such as <spanx style="verb">length</spanx>,
          <spanx style="verb">mimeType</spanx>, and <spanx style="verb">md5</spanx>.</t>
        
        </section>

        <section anchor="event" title="Event">

          <t>In addition to the core properties shared by all Activity Streams
          Objects, "event" objects MAY contain the following properties:</t>

          <texttable>
          <ttcol align="left" width="15%">Property</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left" width="21%">Value</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left">Description</ttcol>

          <c><spanx style="verb">attendedBy</spanx></c>
          <c>Collection object</c>
          <c>A Collection object as defined in Section 3.5 of 
          <xref target="activitystreams"/> that provides information 
          about entities that attended the event.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">attending</spanx></c>
          <c>Collection object</c>
          <c>A Collection object as defined in Section 3.5 of 
          <xref target="activitystreams"/> that provides information 
          about entities that intend to attend the event.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">endTime</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The date and time that the event ends represented as a JSON
          String conforming to the "date-time" production in 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/></c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">invited</spanx></c>
          <c>Collection object</c>
          <c>A Collection object as defined in Section 3.5 of 
          <xref target="activitystreams"/> that provides information 
          about the entities that have been invited to the event.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">maybeAttending</spanx></c>
          <c>Collection object</c>
          <c>A Collection object as defined in Section 3.5 of 
          <xref target="activitystreams"/> that provides information 
          about entities that possibly may attend the event.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">notAttendedBy</spanx></c>
          <c>Collection object</c>
          <c>A Collection object as defined in Section 3.5 of 
          <xref target="activitystreams"/> that provides information 
          about entities that did not attend the event.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">notAttending</spanx></c>
          <c>Collection object</c>
          <c>A Collection object as defined in Section 3.5 of 
          <xref target="activitystreams"/> that provides information about
          e entities that do not intend to attend the event.</c>

          <c><spanx style="verb">startTime</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The date and time that the event begins represented as a JSON
          String conforming to the "date-time" production in 
          <xref target="RFC3339"/></c>
          
          </texttable>
        </section>
        
        <section anchor="issue" title="Issue">
        
          <t>In addition to the core properties shared by all Activity Streams
          Objects, "issue" objects MAY contain the following properties:</t>
          
          <texttable>
          <ttcol align="left" width="15%">Property</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left" width="21%">Value</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left">Description</ttcol>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">types</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> Array</c>
          <c>An array of one or more absolute IRI's that describe the type of
          issue represented by the object.</c>
          </texttable>
        
        </section>

        <section anchor="place" title="Place">
          
          <t>In addition to the core properties shared by all Activity Streams
          Objects, "place" objects MAY contain the following properties:</t>

          <texttable>
          <ttcol align="left" width="15%">Property</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left" width="21%">Value</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left">Description</ttcol>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">position</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> Object</c>
          <c>The latitude, longitude and altitude of the place as a point
          on Earth. Represented as on object with three properties as 
          described below.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">address</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> Object</c>
          <c>A physical address represented as a JSON object with the properties
          defined in the table below.</c>
          
          </texttable>

          <t>The properties for the <spanx style="verb">position</spanx>
          property are:</t>
          
          <texttable>
            <ttcol align="left" width="15%">Property</ttcol>
            <ttcol align="left" width="21%">Value</ttcol>
            <ttcol align="left">Description</ttcol>
            
            <c><spanx style="verb">altitude</spanx></c>
            <c>Number</c>
            <c>The elevation of this point relative to the Earth, in meters 
            above mean sea level. (e.g. 8848.00)</c>
            
            <c><spanx style="verb">latitude</spanx></c>
            <c>Number</c>
            <c>The latitude of this point on Earth in decimal form (e.g. 27.9881)</c>
            
            <c><spanx style="verb">longitude</spanx></c>
            <c>Number</c>
            <c>The longitude of this point on Earth in decimal form (e.g. 86.9253)</c>
          </texttable>
          
          <t>Note that in older versions of this specification, the value of 
          the <spanx style="verb">position</spanx> property was represented 
          as an ISO 6709 compliant String. For instance
          <spanx style="verb">"position":"+27.5916+086.5640+8850/"</spanx>.
          This format has been deprecated and SHOULD NOT be used. However, there
          might be existing deployed applications still utilizing the ISO 6709.
          Consuming implementations can choose to continue supporting the ISO 
          6709 format but SHOULD NOT produce Activity Streams that use the 
          deprecated format.</t>

          <t>The properties for the <spanx style="verb">address</spanx>
          property are:</t>

          <texttable>
          <ttcol align="left" width="15%">Property</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left" width="21%">Value</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left">Description</ttcol>

          <c><spanx style="verb">formatted</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The full mailing address formatted for display or use with 
          a mailing label.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">streetAddress</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The street address including house number, street name, P.O. Box, 
          and extended multi-line address information.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">locality</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The city or locality.</c>
     
          <c><spanx style="verb">region</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The state or region.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">postalCode</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The zip or postal code.</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">country</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The country name component.</c>
          
          </texttable>
        </section>

        <section anchor="task" title="Task">
          
          <t>In addition to the core properties shared by all Activity Streams
          Objects, "task" objects MAY contain the following properties:</t>
          
          <texttable>
          <ttcol align="left" width="15%">Property</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left" width="21%">Value</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left">Description</ttcol>
          
            <c><spanx style="verb">actor</spanx></c>
            <c>Object</c>
            <c>An Activity Streams Object that provides information 
            about the actor that is expected to complete the task.</c>
            
            <c><spanx style="verb">by</spanx></c>
            <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
            <c>A <xref target="RFC3339">"date-time"</xref> specifying
            the date and time by which the task is to be completed.</c>
            
            <c><spanx style="verb">object</spanx></c>
            <c>Object</c>
            <c>An Activity Streams object describing the object of the task.</c>
            
            <c><spanx style="verb">prerequisites</spanx></c>
            <c>Array of Tasks</c>
            <c>An Array of other "task" objects to be completed before this
            task can be completed.</c>
            
            <c><spanx style="verb">required</spanx></c>
            <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> Boolean</c>
            <c>A boolean value indicating whether completion of the task is
            considered to be mandatory or not.</c>
            
            <c><spanx style="verb">supersedes</spanx></c>
            <c>Array of Tasks</c>
            <c>An Array of other "task" objects superseded by this 
            this task object.</c>
            
            <c><spanx style="verb">verb</spanx></c>
            <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
            <c>A String indicating the verb for this task as defined for 
            the <spanx style="verb">verb</spanx> property in an Activity 
            in Section 3.2 of <xref target="activitystreams"/>.</c>
          
          </texttable>
        
        </section>

      </section>

      <section title="Base Extension Properties">
        <t>This specification defines an initial set of extension properties
        that can be used with all activities or objects.</t>

        <section anchor="context" title="Context">
        
          <t>The basic model for an Activity provides properties that allow
          the expression of who (<spanx style="verb">actor</spanx>) performed
          the action, what (<spanx style="verb">object</spanx>) was acted 
          upon, the action (<spanx style="verb">verb</spanx>) that was taken,
          and to what the action was directed (<spanx style="verb">target</spanx>).
          The additional <spanx style="verb">context</spanx> property allows 
          the Activity to further include information about why a particular 
          action occurred by providing details about the context within which 
          a particular Activity was performed. The value of the <spanx style="verb">
          context</spanx> property is an Object of any objectType. The meaning of
          the <spanx style="verb">context</spanx> property is only defined 
          when used within an Activity object.</t>
          
          <t>For example, the following Activity uses the <spanx style="verb">context</spanx>
          property to reference the specific reasons a particular article object
          has been flagged as being inappropriate:</t>
<figure><artwork>
  {
    "actor": {
      "objectType": "person", 
      "displayName": "Joe"
    },
    "verb": "flag-as-inappropriate",
    "object": {
      "objectType": "article",
      "displayName": "An article about stuff"
    },
    "context": {
      "objectType": "issue",
      "displayName": "Terms of Use Violation",
      "url": "http://.../terms-of-use",
      "types": [
        "http://example.org/codes/inappropriateMaterial",
        "http://example.org/codes/copyrightViolation"
      ]
    }
  }
</artwork></figure>
        
        </section>

        <section anchor="location" title="Location">
          <t>Location data can be added to any object type or activity. Location 
          can be specified via geographic coordinates, a street address, 
          a free-form location name or any combination of these.</t>
          
          <t>Within a JSON-serialized Activity Stream, the Location is represented
          using a property named <spanx style="verb">location</spanx> whose 
          value is a <xref target="place">Place</xref> object. The objectType
          property of this object MAY be omitted.</t>
          
          <t>When appearing within an activity, the location data indicates
          the location where the activity occurred. When appearing within an
          object, the location data indicates the location of that
          object at the time the activity occurred.</t>
          
          <t>For example:</t>
<figure><artwork><![CDATA[
  {
    "objectType": "person",
    "displayName": "John Doe",
    "location": {
      "displayName": "Mount Everest",
      "position": {
        "altitude": 8848.00,
        "latitude": 27.9881,
        "longitude": 86.9253
      }
    }
  }
]]></artwork></figure>
          
        </section>

        <section anchor="mood-property" title="Mood">
          <t>Mood describes the mood of the user when the activity was
          performed. This is usually collected via an extra field in the user
          interface used to perform the activity. For the purpose of this
          schema, a mood is a freeform, short mood keyword or phrase along
          with an optional mood icon image.</t>

          <t>In JSON, Moods are included within an object or activity using
          a property named <spanx style="verb">mood</spanx> whose value 
          is a JSON object with the following properties:</t>

          <texttable>
          <ttcol align="left" width="15%">Property</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left" width="21%">Value</ttcol>
          <ttcol align="left">Description</ttcol>

          <c><spanx style="verb">displayName</spanx></c>
          <c><xref target="RFC4627">JSON</xref> String</c>
          <c>The natural-language, human-readable and plain-text keyword or 
          phrase describing the mood. HTML markup MUST NOT be included</c>
          
          <c><spanx style="verb">image</spanx></c>
          <c>Media Link</c>
          <c>An optional image that provides a visual representation of the mood.</c>
          
          </texttable>     
          
          <t>For example:</t>
<figure><artwork><![CDATA[
  {
    "objectType": "note",
    "content": "Working on the activity streams spec",
    "mood": {
      "displayName": "Optimistic",
      "image": "http://example.org/moods/optimistic.png"
    }
  }
]]></artwork></figure>
          
        </section>
        
        <section anchor="rating-property" title="Rating">
          <t>A rating given as a number between 1.0 and 5.0 inclusive with 
          one decimal place of precision. Represented in JSON as a property 
          called <spanx style="verb">rating</spanx> whose value is a JSON 
          number giving the rating.</t>
          
          <t>Ratings are generally most useful only for particular types 
          of objects, such as audio, video, photos and places.</t>
          
          <t>For example:</t>
<figure><artwork><![CDATA[
  {
    "objectType": "review",
    "content": "This is a great product",
    "rating": 3.5
  }
]]></artwork></figure>
          
        </section>
        
        <section anchor="result-property" title="Result">
        
          <t>The <spanx style="verb">result</spanx> provides a description of
          the result of any particular activity. The value of the <spanx style="verb">
          result</spanx> property is an Object of any objectType. The meaning of
          the <spanx style="verb">result</spanx> property is only defined 
          when used within an Activity object.</t>
          
          <t>For instance:</t>
          
<figure><artwork><![CDATA[
  {
    "actor": {
      "objectType": "person", 
      "displayName": "Joe"
    },
    "verb": "complete",
    "object": {
      "objectType": "http://example.org/Exam",
      "displayName": "The Big Exam"
    },
    "result": {
      "score": 123,
      "duration": "P1H",
    }
  }
]]></artwork></figure>

          <t>Use of the <spanx style="verb">result</spanx> property is only
          applicable with certain combinations of verbs and objectTypes. 
          In many cases, the result will be implicit in the combination of 
          actor, verb and object used -- for example, in an activity where
          a person, Joe, creates an article, the result of the activity is 
          clear without the need to specify a separate <spanx style="verb">result</spanx>
          property.</t>
        
        </section>
        
        <section anchor="source" title="Source">
    
          <t>The <spanx style="verb">source</spanx> property provides a reference
          to the original source of an object or activity. The value of the 
          <spanx style="verb">source</spanx> property is an Object of any 
          objectType.</t>
          
          <t>The <spanx style="verb">source</spanx> property is closely related to the 
          <spanx style="verb">generator</spanx> and <spanx style="verb">provider</spanx>
          properties but serves the distinct purpose of identifying where the 
          activity or object was originally published as opposed to identifying 
          the applications that generated or published it.</t>
          
          <t>For example:</t>
<figure><artwork><![CDATA[
  {
    "actor": {
      "objectType": "person",
      "displayName": "Joe"
    },
    "verb": "post",
    "object": {
      "objectType": "photo",
      "image": "http://example.org/photos/fluffycat.jpg"
    },
    "source": {
      "objectType": "collection",
      "displayName": "Joe's Photo's",
      "url": "http://example.org/joes/photos"
    }
  }
]]></artwork></figure>
    
        </section>
    
        <section anchor="startEndTime" title="Starting and Ending Timestamps">
          
          <t>When an long running Activity occurs over a distinct period of 
          time, or when an Object represents a long-running process or event,
          the <spanx style="verb">startTime</spanx> and <spanx style="verb">endTime</spanx>
          properties can be used to specify the date and time at which the activity
          or object begins or concludes. The values for each are represented as 
          JSON Strings conforming to the "date-time" production in <xref target="RFC3339"/>.</t>
          
          <t>For example:</t>
<figure><artwork><![CDATA[
  {
    "actor": {
      "objectType": "person",
      "displayName": "John Doe"},
    "verb": "at",
    "object": {
      "objectType":"place",
      "displayName":"Home"},
    "published": "2012-08-28T03:34:23Z",
    "startTime": "2012-08-12T12:13:14Z",
    "endTime": "2012-08-13T01:34:12Z"
  }  
]]></artwork></figure>

          <t>The <spanx style="verb">startTime</spanx> and 
          <spanx style="verb">endTime</spanx> verbs can be used independently
          or together. If both are specified, the <spanx style="verb">endTime</spanx>
          property MUST specify a moment in time that is more recent that that
          specified by the <spanx style="verb">startTime</spanx> property.</t>

        </section>
        
        <section anchor="tags-property" title="Tags">
          <t>A listing of the objects that have been associated with a 
          particular object using the <spanx style="verb">tag</spanx> verb. 
          Represented in JSON using a property named <spanx style="verb">tags</spanx>
          whose value is  an Array of objects.</t>

          <t>For example:</t>        
<figure><artwork><![CDATA[
  {
    "objectType": "photo",
    "image": "http://example.org/photos/fluffycat.jpg",
    "tags": [
      {
        "objectType": "person",
        "displayName": "John"
      },
      {
        "objectType": "person",
        "displayName": "Jane"
      }
    ]
  }
]]></artwork></figure>     
      </section>
    </section>
    
    <section title="Multi-page Collections" anchor="multipage-collections">
      
      <t>A multi-page collection is a set of linked collection objects that 
      together contain the complete set of objects that can be considered 
      to be members of the collection.</t>
      
      <t>When using multi-paged collections, the following additional properties 
      can be used in addition to the core collection properties defined in section 
      3.5 of <xref target="activitystreams"/>.</t>
      
      <texttable>
        <ttcol>Name</ttcol>
        <ttcol>Value</ttcol>
        <ttcol>Description</ttcol>

        <c><spanx style="verb">itemsAfter</spanx></c>
        <c>String</c>
        <c>An RFC 3339 date-time, as described in Section 3 of 
        <xref target="activitystreams"/>, indicating that the 
        <spanx style="verb">items</spanx> array contains only
        items published or updated after the date and 
        time specified.</c>
        
        <c><spanx style="verb">itemsBefore</spanx></c>
        <c>String</c>
        <c>An RFC 3339 date-time, as described in Section 3 of 
        <xref target="activitystreams"/>, indicating that the 
        <spanx style="verb">items</spanx> array contains only
        items published or updated before the date and time 
        specified.</c>  
        
        <c><spanx style="verb">itemsPerPage</spanx></c>
        <c>Integer</c>
        <c>A non-negative integer specifying the maximum number of 
        objects that will be included in the value of the <spanx style="verb">items</spanx> 
        array.</c>
        
        <c><spanx style="verb">links</spanx></c>
        <c><xref target="links">Links</xref></c>
        <c>Collection of links connecting this collection object
        to the other collection objects containing additional 
        items that can be considered members of the collection.</c>
        
        <c><spanx style="verb">startIndex</spanx></c>
        <c>Integer</c>
        <c>A non-negative integer value identifying the relative 
        position within the collection of the first object contained in 
        the items property. For instance, if there are 20 items that 
        are considered to be members of a collection, but only the last
        10 of those items are serialized within the value of the 
        <spanx style="verb">items</spanx> property, the value of 
        <spanx style="verb">startIndex</spanx> would be 10.</c>
        
      </texttable>
      
      <t>The value of the <spanx style="verb">links</spanx> property 
      is an object as defined in <xref target="links"/>. The properties
      of the object are Registered or Extension Link Relations as defined by 
      <xref target="RFC5988"/>. The following Registered Link Relations are
      identified as having specific purpose for use with Multi-page Collections:</t>
      
      <texttable>
        <ttcol>Name</ttcol>
        <ttcol>Value</ttcol>
        <ttcol>Description</ttcol>
            
        <c><spanx style="verb">first</spanx></c>
        <c><xref target="link-objects">Link Object</xref></c>
        <c>A Link Object referencing the furthest preceding page 
        of the multi-page collection.</c>
            
        <c><spanx style="verb">last</spanx></c>
        <c><xref target="link-objects">Link Object</xref></c>
        <c>A Link Object referencing the furthest following 
        page of the multi-page collection.</c>
            
        <c><spanx style="verb">prev</spanx></c>
        <c><xref target="link-objects">Link Object</xref></c>
        <c>A Link Object referencing the immediately preceding 
        page of the multi-page collection. Note that the property
        name <spanx style="verb">previous</spanx> can be used as an 
        equivalent alternative; however implementations SHOULD use 
        <spanx style="verb">prev</spanx> and MUST NOT use both 
        <spanx style="verb">prev</spanx> AND <spanx style="verb">previous</spanx>
        within the same <spanx style="verb">links</spanx> object.</c>
            
        <c><spanx style="verb">next</spanx></c>
        <c><xref target="link-objects">Link Object</xref></c>
        <c>A Link Object referencing the immediately following 
        page of the multi-page collection.</c>
            
        <c><spanx style="verb">current</spanx></c>
        <c><xref target="link-objects">Link Object</xref></c>
        <c>A Link Object referencing the page containing the items 
        that have been updated or published most recently.</c> 
        
        <c><spanx style="verb">self</spanx></c>
        <c><xref target="link-objects">Link Object</xref></c>
        <c>A Link Object referencing this page.</c>
            
      </texttable>
      
      <figure><preamble>For example, one page of a multi-page 
      collection:</preamble><artwork>
  {
    "totalItems": 12,
    "itemsPerPage" : 10,
    "startIndex": 10,
    "links": {
      "self": {"href":"http://example.org/items?page=1"},
      "next": {"href":"http://example.org/items?page=2"},
      "prev": {"href":"http://example.org/items?page=3"},
      "current": {"href":"http://example.org/items"}
    },
    "items" : [
      {
        "objectType": "person",
        "displayName":"Joe"
      },
      {
        "objectType": "person",
        "displayName":"Sally"
      }
    ]
  }
        </artwork></figure>
        
        <t>Note that, as the example illustrates, the 
        <spanx style="verb">totalItems</spanx> property specifies the total
        number of items that can be considered to be a part of the collection
        as a whole, while the <spanx style="verb">itemsPerPage</spanx> indicates
        the maximum number of objects that will be included in this particular 
        subset. The actual number of objects included in the value of the 
        <spanx style="verb">items</spanx> properly can be equal to or less than 
        either of these values.</t>
      
    </section>
    
    <section title="External Vocabularies" anchor="external-vocabularies">
      
      <t>Any object within an Activity Streams object can be extended with
      additional properties not defined by the <xref target="activitystreams">core
      Activity Streams</xref> specification or this document. Such extension 
      properties can be specific to individual applications or be drawn from 
      other defined vocabularies such as that defined by the Schema.org organization
      and others.</t>
      
      <t>When utilizing such vocabularies, it is possible that conflicts in the
      naming of properties and format of expected values might arise. To mitigate
      the risk of such conflicts, the following guidelines SHOULD be followed:
      
      <list style="numbers">
        <t>When selecting the <spanx style="verb">objectType</spanx> for an
        object, if there is a close equivalent <spanx style="verb">objectType</spanx>
        already defined by this specification, then that <spanx style="verb">objectType</spanx>
        SHOULD be used.</t>
        <t>When properties specific to an external vocabulary are to be included
        within an object, those SHOULD be grouped together under a single 
        "namespace" property whose name is uniquely reflective of the vocabulary.</t>
        <t>When including properties from the external vocabulary, avoid properties
        that are a close semantic match to existing properties defined by this or
        the <xref target="activitystreams">core Activity Streams</xref> specification.
        For example, within the Schema.org vocabulary, the properties
        <spanx style="verb">name</spanx>, <spanx style="verb">description</spanx>, 
        <spanx style="verb">url</spanx> and <spanx style="verb">image</spanx> are
        semantically equivalent to core Activity Streams object properties and 
        therefore SHOULD NOT be used.</t>
        <t>Further, avoid utilizing properties from multiple external vocabularies
        that are similar or semantically equivalent to each other.</t>
      </list>
      </t>
      
      <t>This specification defines the following initial set of "namespace" 
      properties that correspond to specific external vocabularies currently 
      considered to be reasonable candidates for use within Activity Streams
      objects. Future versions of this specification might add additional 
      "namespace" properties to this list. Implementors are free to define
      additional "namespace" properties representing other external vocabularies
      as necessary; however, there is a risk of potential conflicts if multiple 
      independent implementors select the same "namespace" property to represent
      different external vocabularies. To help prevent such conflicts, it is 
      RECOMMENDED that implementors publicly document their use of external 
      vocabularies.</t>
      
      <section title="&quot;dc&quot;" anchor="dc">
        
        <t>The <spanx style="verb">dc</spanx> "namespace" property is
        defined to encapsulate the set of extension properties that
        represent information specific to the <eref target="http://dublincore.org">Dublin 
        Core Metadata Initiative</eref>. If, for instance, Dublin Core properties 
        can be applied to an Activity Streams object, those properties SHOULD be 
        grouped together under the <spanx style="verb">dc</spanx> property.</t>
        
        <figure><preamble>For example:</preamble><artwork>
  {
    "objectType": "file",
    "displayName": "A Document",
    "fileUrl": "http://example.org/foo.html"
    "dc": {
      "format": "text/html; charset="UTF-8"
    }
  }
        </artwork></figure>
        
      </section>
      
      <section title="&quot;geojson&quot;" anchor="geojson">
        
        <t>The <spanx style="verb">geojson</spanx> "namespace" property is defined
        defined to encapsulate the set of extension properties that
        represent information specific to an 
        <eref target="http://www.geojson.org/geojson-spec.html">GeoJSON</eref>
        data type. If, for instance, GeoJSON properties can be applied to
        an Activity Streams object, those properties SHOULD be grouped 
        together under the <spanx style="verb">geojson</spanx> property.</t>
        
        <figure><preamble>For example:</preamble><artwork>
  {
    "objectType": "place",
    "displayName": "A GeoJSON Described Place",
    "geojson": { 
      "type": "FeatureCollection",
      "features": [
        {"type": "Feature",
         "geometry": {
           "type": "Point", 
           "coordinates": [102.0, 0.5]
         },
         "properties": {
           "prop0": "value0"}
         },
         {"type": "Feature",
          "geometry": {
            "type": "LineString",
            "coordinates": [
              [102.0, 0.0], 
              [103.0, 1.0], 
              [104.0, 0.0], 
              [105.0, 1.0]
            ]
          },
          "properties": {
            "prop0": "value0",
            "prop1": 0.0
          }
        },
        {"type": "Feature",
         "geometry": {
           "type": "Polygon",
           "coordinates": [
             [[100.0, 0.0], 
              [101.0, 0.0], 
              [101.0, 1.0],
              [100.0, 1.0], 
              [100.0, 0.0]]]
           },
           "properties": {
             "prop0": "value0",
             "prop1": {"this": "that"}
           }
         }
      ]
    }
  }
        </artwork></figure>
        
      </section>
      
      <section title="&quot;ld&quot;" anchor="ld">
        
        <t>The <spanx style="verb">ld</spanx> "namespace" property is defined
        to encapsulate the set of extension properties that represent information
        specific to the <eref target="http://json-ld.org/">JSON Linked Data</eref>
        vocabulary. If, for instance, Linked Data properties can be applied to
        an Activity Streams object, those properties SHOULD be grouped 
        together under the <spanx style="verb">ld</spanx> property.</t>
        
        <figure><preamble>For example:</preamble><artwork>
 {
   "objectType": "person",
   "displayName": "John Doe",
   "ld": {
     "@context": "http://json-ld.org/contexts/person.ld",
     "@id": "http://example.org/john.doe",
     "born": "1929-12-12"
   }
 }
        </artwork></figure>
        
      </section>
      
      <section title="&quot;links&quot;" anchor="links">
 
        <t>The <spanx style="verb">links</spanx> "namespace" property is defined
        to encapsulate the set of extension properties that represent links to 
        external resources. Property names are defined as being either Registered
        or Extension Link Relation Types as defined by <xref target="RFC5988"/>.
        The list of currently known Registered Link Relations can be found within the
        <eref target="http://www.iana.org/assignments/link-relations/link-relations.xml">
        IANA Registry of Link Relations</eref>.</t>
        
        <figure><preamble>For example:</preamble><artwork>
  {
    "objectType": "note",
    "displayName": "This is a simple note",
    "links": {
      "canonical": {
        "href":"http://www.example.org/notes/123"
      },
      "edit": {
        "href":"http://www.example.org/api/notes/123"
      }
    }
  }
        </artwork></figure>
        
        <t>The value of each property within the <spanx style="verb">links</spanx>
        object is either a single Link Object as defined in <xref target="link-objects"/> 
        or an array of Link Objects in the case where multiple links with the same 
        Link Relation must be specified.</t>
        
        <t>When the value is specified as an array of Link Objects, the ordering
        of values within the array is considered insignificant. Each contained
        value is to be treated as a separate link. An array SHOULD NOT contain
        multiple Link Objects specifying the same <spanx style="verb">href</spanx> value.</t>
      
        <t>When using extension link relation types, the property name can be 
        specified as an <xref target="RFC3987">IRI</xref> but MUST be converted to 
        <xref target="RFC3986">URIs</xref> when compared and dereferenced as required 
        by Section 4.2 of <xref target="RFC5988"/>.</t>
      
        <t>As defined in Section 3 of <xref target="RFC5988"/>, such properties
        can be viewed as statements of the form "The containing object has a 
        {relation type} resource at {target IRI}" where the {relation type} is
        identified by the property name, and the {target IRI} is provided by the 
        property value.</t>
        
        <section title="Link Objects" anchor="link-objects">
          
          <t>All links are expressed as JSON objects that MUST contain an 
          <spanx style="verb">href</spanx> property whose value is an 
          absolute <xref target="RFC3987">IRI</xref> providing the target of
          the link. The object MAY contain the following additional properties:</t>
          
          <texttable>
            <ttcol>Name</ttcol>
            <ttcol>Value</ttcol>
            <ttcol>Description</ttcol>
            
            <c><spanx style="verb">hreflang</spanx></c>
            <c><xref target="RFC4646">Language Tag</xref></c>
            <c>A hint that identifies the language of the target resource.</c>
            
            <c><spanx style="verb">title</spanx></c>
            <c>JSON String</c>
            <c>A human-readable descriptive label for the link.</c>
            
            <c><spanx style="verb">type</spanx></c>
            <c>JSON String</c>
            <c>A hint that identifies the media type of the linked resource.</c>
          </texttable>
          
          <t>Link Objects MAY contain an <spanx style="verb">objectType</spanx>
          property with the value <spanx style="verb">link</spanx>.</t>
          
          <t>Additional properties MAY be specified but are undefined by 
            this specification.</t>
          
        </section>
        
      </section>
      
      <section title="&quot;odata&quot;" anchor="odata">
        
        <t>The <spanx style="verb">odata</spanx> "namespace" property is 
        defined to encapsulate the set of extension properties that represent
        information specific to the <eref target="http://www.odata.org/">OData</eref>
        specification. If, for instance, OData properties can be applied to 
        an Activity Streams object, those properties SHOULD be grouped 
        together under the <spanx style="verb">odata</spanx> property.</t>
        
        <figure><preamble>For example:</preamble><artwork>
 {
   "objectType": "person",
   "displayName": "John Doe",
   "odata": {            
     "__metadata": { ... },
     "com.example.user.kind" : "PAID",
     "CustomerID": "JDOE",
     "UserName": "jdoe",
   }
 }
        </artwork></figure>
        
      </section>
      
      <section title="&quot;opengraph&quot;" anchor="opengraph">
        
        <t>The <spanx style="verb">opengraph</spanx> "namespace" property is
        defined to encapsulate the set of extension properties that
        represent information specific to an 
        <eref target="https://developers.facebook.com/docs/opengraph/">OpenGraph</eref>
        data type. If, for instance, OpenGraph properties can be applied to
        an Activity Streams object, those properties SHOULD be grouped 
        together under the <spanx style="verb">opengraph</spanx> property.</t>
        
        <figure><preamble>For example:</preamble><artwork>
  {
    "objectType": "person",
    "displayName": "John Smith",
    "opengraph": {
      "username": "john_smith",
      "verified": false,
      "relationship_status": "Single"
    }
  }
        </artwork></figure>
        
      </section>
      
      <section title="&quot;schema_org&quot;" anchor="schema_org">
        
        <t>The <spanx style="verb">schema_org</spanx> "namespace" property is 
        defined to encapsulate the set of extension properties that represent
        information specific to a <eref target="http://schema.org">Schema.org</eref>
        data type. If, for instance, Schema.org properties can be applied to 
        an Activity Streams object, those properties SHOULD be grouped 
        together under the <spanx style="verb">schema_org</spanx> property.</t>
        
        <figure><preamble>For example:</preamble><artwork>
  {
    "objectType": "person",
    "displayName": "John Smith",
    "schema_org": {
      "additionalType": ["http://schema.org/Person"]
      "birthDate": ["1976-12-23"],
      "gender": ["Male"]
    }
  }
        </artwork></figure>
                
      </section>
      
    </section>
    
  </middle>

  <back>
    <references title="Normative References">
  &rfc2119;
  &rfc1951;
  &rfc1952;
  &rfc3339;
  &rfc4627;
  &rfc4646;
  &rfc3986;
  &rfc3987;
  &rfc5988;
      <reference anchor="activitystreams">
        <front>
          <title>JSON Activity Streams 1.0</title>

    <author fullname="James M Snell" initials="J.M." surname="Snell">
      <organization>IBM</organization>
    </author>

    <author fullname="Martin Atkins" initials="M." surname="Atkins">
      <organization>SAY Media</organization>
    </author>

    <author fullname="Will Norris" initials="W." surname="Norris">
      <organization>Google</organization>
    </author>

    <author fullname="Chris Messina" initials="C." surname="Messina">
      <organization>Citizen Agency, Google</organization>
    </author>

    <author fullname="Monica Wilkinson" initials="M." surname="Wilkinson">
      <organization>MySpace, Facebook, Socialcast</organization>
    </author>

    <author fullname="Rob Dolin" initials="R." surname="Dolin">
      <organization>Microsoft</organization>
    </author>

          <date month="May" year="2011" />
        </front>
      </reference>
    </references>

  </back>
</rfc>
